Hey. Hey. Hey.
Heat.
Hello, good evening and good day
everybody. body and welcome back to the
Ask Show. This is episode 337
and we are discussing the situation in
West Asia, the ongoing war uh that's
been launched by the by the US and
Israel on Iran and it's escalating. It's
escalating and it's expanding. So, we're
going to discuss all that today and
hopefully maybe some other things as
well. So, before we do that, let's see
who all is there on the live stream on
the live chat. Fraud hawk sona sanduji
atul mishra football bakisenberg
big do man big dozen fraud hawk once
again really now Patel namaskar
um rrook rrook moneya hello jind uh niga
x raika jashuram geopol geopolitical dub
from indoritana
namaste him geopolitical dub once again
namaste ram
Soldier boy Saksham Jaserotia General
Subuta hello um Pratt Dana once again
who else Manhattan I6W hello
Ashwani Humanity survives Abhinav Capil
Samanik Kakashi Kakashi 2409 Chakraorti
Aush Singh hello Pranam Sarji Abinav
Kapali Binav Capil Ajinka Manhattan
Rohan Biri Juram Rahul Dunak Namaskar
good to see you anime Parata. Hello.
Omnayak Swami. Noise. Noises.
Alka Shikari. Namaste. Anime Paratia.
Thank you sir. Thank you. Yes. The
recent podcast. Thank you. Thank you so
much. Ajinka Paw Shadow. Uh Anand
Payurang Rola. Uh Heisenberg. Hello.
Good name. Good to see you again. Uh
Hamida Beum is here from Azarbaijan.
Good to have you ma'am. uh iron flame
adita kja Mr. Said the board particle,
Sudhar the Gimir, uh Jant Tiswani,
Anand Singh, Oberoy, the Chundra Shikhar
limit, Wakam uh Chandra Kant, real Badir
Putin, good to see you, Jam Abishek,
Shawastav and everyone else. As Benor,
good to see you, Ba Bushetti, Har
Krishna,
uh and everyone else.
Thank you so much for being on the live
chat. So uh before I start taking
questions, let's first discuss uh what's
happened in the last uh few days, last
couple of days essentially. Let's
discuss what's happened in the last
couple of days since we did the last
live stream. So the war is going on.
Iran is retaliating hard. Uh there is a
news blackout, a significant news
blackout from Israel. So we don't quite
know what's happening. Uh it's pretty
clear that Israel is taking a lot of
well a lot of missile hits from Iran.
It's it's very clear u
Iran has apparently exhausted its
stockpile of old missiles. It's now
using more modern missiles, missiles
that have cluster munitions, cluster
warheads. So before a missile gets into
the range of an interceptor, it uh
releases a cluster of warheads like 50
60 warheads.
Then how does an interceptor deal with
those? So it essentially defeats the
purpose of the interceptors.
That's what the Iranians are doing right
now. They have well come up with new
technology,
cluster warheads.
And that goes back to the old adage of
quantity has a quality of its own. And
of course uh Iran has a tremendous uh
quantity of missiles and drones. It's
it's very clear. So Israel it looks like
it's taking a real pounding. uh the Gulf
states whichever whichever nations are
harboring American military bases they
have taken hits on those military bases
and maybe also on the fuel supply fuel
uh
oil refineries etc
the oil production facilities right uh
it looks like it's possible that much if
not most of the American military
infrastructure in the Gulf region may
possibly be destroyed. Trillions of
dollars worth of American infrastructure
possibly may have been destroyed. A lot
of radars are taking hits. Very
expensive radars.
A $1.1 billion radar was taken out by
the Iranians recently
and other radars too. So the so it means
that there's only so these warnings
these radars are early warning radars.
You destroy those radars, you don't get
early warnings of missile or drone
strikes. So when you get a warning,
you've got like a few seconds to react.
That's what's happening in Israel in in
in these nations wherever the Americans
have military bases. Right? So that's
what's happening. I Iran is taking a big
pounding, massive pounding.
Uh it looks like the Americans are
carpet bombing Thran, right? So
tremendous damage in Thran to
infrastructure, civilian infrastructure.
must be I don't know God knows how many
civilian lives are being lost every day
but that's war I suppose the same thing
is happening in Tel Aiv um so that's the
situation u I've seen some satellite
images of uh Iranian airports being
targeted Iranian aircraft being being
destroyed so there's destruction all
around
Iran obviously has hit out at various
Gulf nations uh there have been uh
reports that Iran has targeted various
oil production facilities. Iran has
claimed that the attacks on Saudi Arabia
etc were not done by Iran. So Iran is
essentially saying that these are these
are false flag attacks perhaps carried
out by allegedly by Israel. Maybe that's
what Iran is claiming. Uh there's been
attacks drone attacks on Azarbaijan too
and Iran again claimed that these were
not but done by Iran which means the
Iran is claiming these are false flag
attacks done by Israel perhaps
uh Azarbaijan could could be in the
crosshairs of Iran unfortunately because
Azarbaijan is a major oil producing
nation and a significant portion of
Israel's oil imports come from
Azarbaijan.
So that's that's an evolving situation.
Um Donald Trump has perhaps
perhaps given possibly a go-ahehead to
various militias, Kurdish militias, etc.
to invade Iran and try and take over
territory and perhaps attempt regime
change or at least destabilize Iran. So
we are once again seeing the good old
American strategy of proxy warfare of
using proxy militias and proxy
armed forces, armed groups, non-state
actors, etc. against against a sovereign
nation we we are very familiar with that
in India the Americans used Pakistan to
unleash terrorism on India from the 80s
onwards. Oh. Uh, yeah. So that that's
that's an ongoing situation, an evolving
situation, and that's not going to
please Turkey.
The the American use of Kuresh forces.
And apparently the Americans have
betrayed the Kuresh people at least
seven or eight times before. So why
would the Kurds want to once again be
used by the Americans? I suppose there
are people who are being paid off to do
this. absorb. So now let's take a look
at some of the uh developments that I
have been able to find on Twitter.
Twitter is suppressing news. Now Twitter
is suppressing news of what's happening.
Okay, you you're not getting the latest
news anymore on Twitter. The Twitter
algorithm has been tweaked such that it
promotes what the Americans are saying,
the American official narrative, but the
narrative from the other side is now
being suppressed and there's almost no
news coming in from Israel. You know, no
videos coming from Israel. So clearly
things are not going well
in yeah
for Israel
looks like the uh Iron Dome system has
finally run out possibly possibly run
out of uh the majority of its
interceptors. they'll still have some in
reserve obviously for high value targets
but uh it looks like the mood on the
ground the sentiment on the on the
ground in Israel is that the iron dome
has now failed which means the Israeli
Iranian missiles are essentially you
know they're hitting on demand
the number of missiles Iran is launching
is decreasing every day but the
effectiveness seems to be just the same
so earlier if on one day they launched
100 missiles to start to to strike 10
targets perhaps
Maybe today they're launching 20
missiles and still getting 10 hits
and Iran has also been launching drone
strikes and and maybe drones are now
taking precedence or missiles.
So it's an evolving situation. The fact
of the matter is Iran has not been
defeated. Iran is far from being
defeated and looks like this entire war
may have been a mistake by the Americans
by Trump. Looks like he gambled. It will
be a two-day war and I'll get the
Iranians to come to the negotiating
table immediately. Hasn't worked out.
The straight of hormones is closed.
First time in history. Oil prices are
shooting up now and that's going to have
global repercussions. It's going to be a
global shock, right? And as a
consequence of hormones shutting down
which accounts for what at least 20% of
the world's oil supply
that's why the world now has no option
but to look for alternatives and what
what is the alternative
it's Russia Russian oil
so suddenly the entire world
can't do without Russian oil and the
Americans have magnanimously given India
permission to buy Russian oil that we'll
discuss later separately.
But right now the situation is such that
Russia without Russia there's going to
be oil shocks in the world. Russia is
going to have to fill in the gaps big
gaps
that gives immense geopolitical leverage
to Vladimir Putin and to Russia
immense geopolitical leverage. And the
longer the situation continues, the more
leverage Russia gets. The Americans are
desperate to open Hormos to reopen the
street of Hormos.
But American ships can't come near the
region.
Even the most powerful warships, the
Americans have the aircraft carriers
have been moved much further away from
the state of Hormos because they'll be
targeted by the Iranians. So in that
case, in that situation, how do the
Americans reopen Hormuz? Not going to
happen anytime soon unless they can
genuinely suppress Iran's missile
capabilities and drone capabilities.
That that seems like wishful thinking
right now. So the straight of Horos
looks like it's going to remain closed
for the foreseeable future for for a few
weeks at least,
right? So the longer this lasts, the
more leverage Russia gets
and therefore it's in Russia's interest
that this war goes on as long as
possible.
Now Russia can try to start start
leveraging
its its leverage in terms of oil in
other things maybe in the Ukraine war.
So Russia's Russia's importance has
suddenly risen in the world and American
stockpiles of weapons and munitions are
declining drastically.
The first two or three days of the war
used up 20 30% of the global tomahawk
missile supply of the US.
The Americans and Europeans have been,
you know, supplying Ukraine with all of
their surplus or maybe more than surplus
weapons, munitions. Now everyone's
running low.
What if China decides tomorrow morning
to take Taiwan?
What does the US do then? They'll press
Japan into action, South Korea into
action.
You see, the longer this lasts
and the longer Iran can remain
resilient, the weaker uh a position the
US will find itself in. And it can't
suddenly ramp up supplies, ramp up
production of missiles and
weapons and munitions overnight. It
doesn't have the capability to do that.
It may take several months before they
can start ramping up production. What
happens in the meanwhile? In the next
few months, the whole world may change.
Maybe borders may change. There are
nations waiting for opportunities. You
may know some of those nations.
Uh so now, so that is the situation
right now. Now, now let's take a look at
uh some of the information I've been
able to let's say find on Twitter. Okay,
we'll we'll take a look at some of this.
So this this is from March 6th. New
satellite imagery released by Airbus
confirms that the ENTPY2
terminal high altitude area defense
radar at the MOA Salty base in
Jordan was destroyed by Iran. The US is
denying it, but the satellite images
don't lie. This is a $1.1 billion radar.
Okay. And more than one of these radars
have been destroyed. And there's only a
handful like 20 21 radars in the entire
world. the Americans may have to bring
in some radars from South Korea or
Japan,
right? So, what happens to South Korea
and Japan's defense? So, this is one
thing that's happened. What else? That's
another one. Okay, this is the same one
apparently. Moaf Fakali air base in in
in Jordan. So clearly the Americans are
trying to deny this is this has
happened. But it's but it's very clear
that they've lost this incredibly
valuable radar that kind of leaves its
their allies blind.
Right. What else?
Stop that. We'll stop. No. No. Stop.
Pause. Pause.
And I pause this.
Okay. I'll mute this. So Indian
journalist Raj Mahan Singh returning
from Israel drops a truth bomb. Even
bunkers are unsafe. People died deep
inside their bunkers. Iranian missiles
sometimes hit without sirens. Israeli
government blocks hospital access,
hidden casualties, lies about its losses
and doesn't allow filming. Okay. So
that's a report by an Indian journalist
who has come back and there's a there's
a longer uh transcript. When a missile
strikes it does not differentiate
whether you are Indian or Israeli
because Indians face racism apparently
in Israel. It's just rhetoric that
bunkers protect you. I saw people dying
in 100 foot deep bunkers and they
Israelis don't tell you the facts. Press
freedom in India is much better than in
Israel. We are thankful to the Indian
government etc. It provides details. In
Israel the government does not tell you
anything at all. You cannot film the
dead bodies. as well. I can understand
why and you cannot visit the hospitals.
When an incident takes place, we are not
we are not given the details of the
location. The next day when we visit the
site, we are told there was only one
casualty but lo a local told us there
were four houses and everyone died which
shows there was a major incident. We are
told Israel has robust technology.
However, let me tell you that one day
early in the morning there were no
sirens. Missiles struck without any
warning. the technology fails and it's
hard to determine when drones and
missiles will strike. You must have
heard by now that Iran targeted almost
every US embassy in the Middle East and
maybe they targeted tried targeting it
in Telaw 2. We would not have s survived
there and this person was trapped in
Israel from February 28 to March 6.
Journalist Brahman Singh sad news. Okay,
so that's what's happened there. Now we
have this three of the big four Gulf
countries Saudi Arabia, UE, Kuwait and
Qatar are discussing withdrawing from US
and other investments as the toll from
the war with Iran mounts as per uh
uh foreign as per FD.
Yeah. So that's that's going on. There
are strains between
these nations and their and the United
States, right? Uh what else do we have?
An interesting piece of information has
come out of North America. A swarm of
over a 100 earthquakes ranging from
magnitude 1 to 4.3 occurred near the
Tonoba test test range in Nevada, USA in
early March 2026
causing speculation about potential
covert nuclear testing. While the
location is at near is near historical
nuclear test sites. Uh scientists
believe naturally of course that these
tremors including a 4.3 magnitude event
are natural seismic activity.
Okay. Uh
right. So looks like the Americans are
doing covered nuclear testing. Obviously
their scientists will say it's all
natural. Uh today the news has come that
Iran's interim interiming leadership
council has approved that neighboring
countries will no longer be attacked
unless an attack on Iran originates from
them and they have said that we are not
attacking those countries we are
attacking American uh military
installations that are hosted by those
countries right so so this is obviously
it makes a lot of sense strategically so
what Iran has done is first of all it
has destroyed American assets in the
neighboring countries. It has most
likely destroyed much of the American
military infrastructure in these
countries. Probably trillions of dollars
worth of infrastructure. Okay, it's done
that. It's destroyed that. And obviously
these countries are being targeted
because they are cooperating with the
Americans and the Israelis. These
countries, I suppose, have no choice.
But yeah, so these countries are
harboring American military bases from
which attacks on Iran are being
launched. So Iran has destroyed most
likely those uh American military bases
and facilities. Now obviously these
countries are being targeted. I mean Abu
Dhabi is has been targeted. Dubai is
currently I mean today it was targeted I
believe right? Uh there was a drone
strike on the Dubai International
Airport.
If an airport is targeted where you have
where typically you have civilian
civilian flights I mean that brings the
country to a halt right. So these
countries are being targeted because
they are harboring American bases. So
clearly these countries are now
realizing that the American the
so-called American uh military umbrella
of protection is is worth nothing.
America is not able the US is not able
to protect these countries.
Right? So this this is this was not a
good strategy you know having American
military base on our on our territory.
Right? Uh so obviously this will be a
lesson that these countries will learn
that this was not a good idea having
American bases and all that and
believing the Americans and Iran is
saying that look we are not targeting
you you we are targeting the American
bases. So now long term there's going to
be a a choice that the Gulf nations are
will have to face. Do we keep hosting
American bases which will guarantee that
we'll be targeted by the Iranians or or
shall we now distance ourselves from the
Americans
and thereby lose this imaginary military
security umbrella of the Americans.
Right? That's the uh choice these Gulf
nations have. Now what else is
happening?
Okay. March 5th, India's foreign
secretary Vikram Misri
met the Iranian ambassador Dr. Muhammad
Fatali at the embassy of Iran. And Mr.
Misri our foreign secretary paid
condolences over the assassination of
Supreme Leader Kame.
Okay. So this has happened. What else
has happened? Look here. Same thing.
Foreign for foreign secretary Vikramar
Musli on behalf of on behalf of the
government of India obviously signed the
condolence book at the Iran embassy. The
book has been opened after the killing
of assassination of supreme leader Kam.
So the government of India has now given
its condolences to the people of Iran
and typically when when a world leader
is assassinated you would have the prime
minister who would do this but the prime
minister has refrain from refrain from
doing that but the government of India
through its through the uh foreign
secretary the highest bureaucrat in the
foreign ministry has paid condolences to
the people of Iran over the
assassination of Mr. Kami. What else Dr.
J. Shankar,
India's foreign minister met with uh
Iran's deputy foreign minister Katib
Zade in Delhi on the 6th of March.
Right? And we can see that they are in
discussions. We also met with US Deputy
Deputy Secretary of State Christopher
Lando.
Right. What else do we have about the
sinking of about the destruction of the
Iranian warship which we had discussed
in the last last uh episode of
Askabujit.
So it turns out that that Iranian
warship obviously we know that it was it
had participated in uh naval exercises
in India. It was then returning home and
while it was near Sri Lanka, south of
Sri Lanka, it had requested the
government of Sri Lanka to give access
to to to gull the port
so that it can dock at the port because
so they had requested access and it
looks like the this Iranian ship was
made to wait for 8 between 8 to 11 hours
and that's how the American submarine
caught up with it and torpedoed
Okay, that's that's interesting
information that's come out. Now,
there's another Iranian vessel,
Bushaher, that requested entry into Sri
Lankan waters on March 4th.
Okay. A few hours after the American
forces sank the other ship, Dana.
And uh this ship has apparently now been
uh given entry into Sri Lankan waters.
It is it has docked in the Sri Lankan
port.
So that's a development and India has
provided refuge to a third Iranian
warship now Lavan and it is now docked
in Kochi.
Uh this ship had refu requested for
refuge on 28th Feb was given approval on
the 1st March and has been docked in the
port since 4th of March and the crew of
183 shipmen have been accommodated at
naval facilities.
So, right, that's going on. That's
what's going on. What else?
Now, this is Yeah, about the oil and gas
production thing and all that. Uh, this
is the American Treasury Secretary Scott
Bessent. He says he said yesterday,
President Trump's energy agenda has
resulted in oil and gas production
reaching the highest levels were
recorded. That's fine. What else? To
enable oil to keep flowing into the
global market. I mean, he's obviously
talking about hormones here, but he is
saying that America has done great. So
to enable oil to keep flowing into the
global market, the Treasury Department
is issuing a temporary 30-day waiver to
allow Indian refiners to purchase India
uh Russian oil. This deliberately
short-term measure will not provide
significant financial benefit to the
Russian government as it only authorizes
transactions involving oil already
stranded at sea.
India is an essential partner of the US
and we fully anticipate that New Delhi
will ramp up ramp up purchases of
American oil. This stop gap measure will
alleviate pressure caused by Iran's
attempt to take global security hostage.
Put all the blame on Iran when you cause
the situation. So look at the language
he has used. The Americans are issuing a
temporary 30-day waiver to India.
They're essentially giving India
permission.
They're giving India permission
magnanimously.
Okay.
What does it mean? It means they are
portraying to the whole world that they
give they have given India permission
because earlier earlier India did not
have permission from from them that's
why India could not do certain things
and the government of India has not
responded to this at all.
I know for a fact that India had not
stopped purchasing Russian oil when the
uh temporary framework for the trade
deal happened between India and the US.
The American there was nothing about
Russian oil in in in the in the
communicate given out by India and the
US but the Americans then put out a
separate communicate in which they
claimed that India will have to stop
purchasing Russian oil if it wants the
trade deal to happen and India will be
monitored and India once again didn't
say anything at the time. India doesn't
want to antagonize the Americans. That's
why India is not responding to these
ridiculous claims by the Americans. And
the Americans are trying to impose
pressure on India. They're trying to arm
twist India. They're trying to, you
know, use whatever leverage, all the
leverage they have on India to force
India to stop buying Russian oil. They
want to take control of India's energy
policy.
Okay. I don't think India has given into
the Americans. India has been purchasing
Russian oil throughout. India has not
not stopped purchasing Russian oil
but now they are saying we are giving
India temporary permission so they are
trying to signal to the world that we
control the Indians
which is incorrect they don't
but India is making it making it a point
to avoid a verbal confrontation with the
Americans at this point in time India is
being differential because they are a
much more powerful nation and let's b
our
So the Americans are trying to make it
look like they they control our energy
policy. Okay. So so the that's the
statement uh Scott Bessent has put out.
That's about the Iran war. Now we will
discuss that in detail. But here's a
couple of other interesting things. Um
the US de deputy secretary of state
Christopher Lando was in Delhi yesterday
day before yesterday whenever it was for
the risina event and he said that the US
won't give India the same kind of
economic advantages it gave China
which allowed that country to emerge as
a major competitor.
Here's the readout. The US won't give
India the same kind of economic
advantages it gave China which allowed
that country to emerge as a major
competitor. Deputy Secretary of State
Christopher Landandor said on Thursday,
signaling Washington's cautiousness in
negotiations over trade deal. While the
US wants to work with India to unlock
India's limitless potential quote
unquote, India should understand,
India should understand that we are not
going to make the same mistakes with
India that we made with China 20 years
ago.
Lando also offered to work with India to
address long and short-term issues blah
blah to me to in meeting its energy
challenges
and so on. So
the US is not going to make the same
mistakes with India that we made with
China 20 years ago. If you are a viewer
of this channel, you will have heard me
say the same thing dozens of time times
over the past few years. The Americans
are not going to make the same mistakes
with India that they made with China.
And now the American deputy secretary of
state is repeating what I have been
saying for for for the past two three
years that the Americans will not make
the same mistakes with India that they
made with China. They aided and admitted
the rise of China. They will not make
that mistake with India. Exactly what
I've been saying for years. The guy
repeated those exact words. The American
Deputy Secretary of State. Their policy
is not of
of helping India, it's of containing
India. What was the thing? We won't give
the same kind of economic advantages to
India. So they want to control India.
They want India to be on their side and
no and not independent, not sovereign.
They want to control India's energy
policy and other policies, but they
don't want to give economic advantages
to India. And in other words, what does
the US seek? It seeks a vasal in India.
It seeks they seek to make India their
their largest bason. That's what the
Americans seek and they are pretty open
and blatant about it now. Pretty open.
They've used exactly the same words I've
been using.
So that's the situation.
That's what the Americans want with
respect to India.
Okay. Now let's come back. So that's
essentially what's happened. I've taken
about 30 minutes or so to explain what's
happening in the world. Now, now let's
take some questions.
Pratar Dhana says GCC is are threatening
to pull out their dollars from the US.
Do they want to stop the war? Do they
even want the war? Did they even want
the war in the first place or is it all
Trump Netanyahu? The GCC nations did not
ever want this war. The GCC nations want
stability and peace in the region. When
you have a nation like the UAE that has
spent so much time, energy, money in
building up its economy and positioning
the country as a safe he haven for
wealthy people around the world, kind of
like a Switzerland of the Middle East.
Why will a nation like the UAE want a
war in the region? The UAE never wanted
a war in the first place. Saudi Arabia
did not want a war. Everyone knows that.
Everyone knew if if a war happens the
straight of hormones could be impacted.
UAE is a major oil exporter. The UAE
knew this. Saudi Saudi Arabia knew it.
All these nations knew it. Kuwait knew
it. Kuwait's
only export to the world is is oil. Its
entire economy depends on oil.
These nations never wanted a war.
Right? It is Trump and Netanya who have
dragged dragged them all into this war.
Uh do they so do the GCC nations want to
stop the war? Now it's beyond their
control.
Now it's beyond their control. The
Americans decide what happens. Of
course, if they threaten threaten to
pull out their investments from the US
trillions of dollars, then maybe Trump
may consider it or he may take
heavy-handed action against them also.
Trump is is liable to do such things. So
yes, the these nations want to stop the
war. The longer the war lasts, the more
these nations get disrupted. People, if
this war lasts for a few months, people
may never return to Dubai. All the
wealthy expatriots who live in Dubai,
including lots of Indians, they won't
return.
The aura of stability, the aura of
peace, the aura of all that will be
permanently shattered. So, so the GCC
nations want to stop the war. They are
desperate to stop the war
and they've taken damage right so they
did not want the war at all. It is Trump
and Netanyahu or maybe Netanyahu and
Trump who have dragged them into this
conflict.
Kakashi says why are why are all Indians
firmly supporting the US and Israel?
They don't believe the US is stopping
India's rise through all these wars.
They think US is good and Iran is evil.
Look, what I would say is that as
Indians, you should not bet on one horse
or the other. This is not your war. I
don't know why Indians have this
slaveminded behavior. Why do they have
this impurity complex that they have to
support somebody and they they hero
worship certain nations?
My stand is that I am neutral in this.
This war doesn't benefit India in any
way whatsoever. It harms India's
interests which is why this war needs to
end.
Right? And I support no party in this. I
support India. My support is always for
India.
And I will analyze the events as per my
understanding. I have a
decent understanding of the world.
Right? And maybe I have some biases.
My bias is I'm biased towards India.
That's my bias. I'm not biased towards
any of these sides. So why are all
Indians doing this? Because Indians
don't think right. Indians don't
understand the world. Indians don't have
the ability to think critically and
Indians hero worship some nations. I
can't blame Indians for that. Blame the
education system. So that's the problem.
That is the issue. Right? And of course
the the US is is they've they've had
this policy of containing India since
2022. A containment policy.
They are going to do everything it takes
to stop or or or to India's rise
to slow down India's growth. The
Americans are doing it pretty openly.
But Indians don't see this. They don't
understand the nuances, right? Indians
don't and and the Indian media won't
report it in those words.
So that's why Indians don't understand
what's happening and they are supporting
whatever nation. There are Indians who
are supporting Iran too, right? There
are Indians who are supporting Iran as
well. So, a bunch of Indians supporting
Iran, a bunch of Indians supporting
Israel, a bunch of Indians supporting
the US. Will you ever support India?
Football Bak, thank you very much sir or
ma'am indeed. Thank you so much.
Kakashi says I am right-wing but I'm not
pro- west. Are Indian right-wingers pro-
west or what?
Okay, so I'm right-wing but I'm not pro
west. Right-wing Indians blindly
following US-based accounts like Aravind
and listening to Indian origin soldiers
as a disgrace. Yes, there was some
Indian origin u female sold American
soldier who apparently made made a video
about something. I didn't watch it but
looks like she's trying to influence
Indian opinion and trying to make
Indians uh support the US perhaps in
Israel perhaps. I don't know. uh this
Aravind account is very interesting.
I generally don't talk about these
things about individuals. I don't care.
But this Aravind account
uh people consider this this account
Nostradamus Indian Nostradamus. He makes
predictions and all come true. The
account is based in the US. Okay. You
can see on Twitter or X you can see
where which geography the account is
based in. So the account is based in the
US. Aravind
it's got
they've not whoever it is has not put
their face on the account they've put
somebody else's face on the account as
the display picture profile picture so
we don't know who it is who's running
the account the person clearly knows
about India in great detail maybe of
Indian origin perhaps
but that person
acti you know that person triggers my
sixth sense
Yeah, that person is most likely that
account is a SCOP account, psychological
operation account. 98% of the things
they will say will be pro- India and in
there slightly they will slip in
American propaganda and that too very
nicely done very carefully done such
such that it looks like it's pro- India
there are other accounts like this there
are Chinese SCOP accounts SL can SL
Kchan is another guy who's that guy
shows his face he's obviously an Indian
who isn't who I don't know it's possible
he's on China's as payroll. Maybe he
loves China. Maybe he's doing it out of
the out of the goodness of his heart, El
Can or maybe he's paid by the Chinese
government. Whichever way, he's entirely
pro-China. All he tweets about is China,
China, China, China, China. Even the
Chinese uh foreign ministry spokesperson
or the Chinese embassy in India
spokesperson have retweeted Ara, sorry,
this Slanton person.
So that's pretty openly pro-China. But
this Aravind account sounds like a very
pro- India account but it is a
psychological operations account.
So I would request you all don't believe
anonymous accounts
and be very careful about what you
consume and what you believe believe the
information that you consume and
believe.
I am so I'm glad that other people are
understanding that these are SCOB
accounts. I mean it's an anonymous
account with somebody else's face on the
profile. We don't know what what he or
she is, who it is, what the real name is
and people are just following this
account and my god falling for the
nonsense, falling for the propaganda.
Anu giant says as Iranian attacked top
secret Iran Israeli nuke site Sto Mikah
and destroyed radars they can also
attack Dimuna nuclear plant and cause
radiation leak. Agreed.
Of course theoretically it's possible. I
don't know about uh Iran having attacked
uh Bikha. Have they done that? I'm not
sure. Let's let's try and find out what
is the Bikha.
Give me a second.
Okay, let's do a search. Give me a
second. Once again. Okay. What happened
to Sto Mika?
Sto Mikha Air Base.
Okay. Center of Israel. Is that been in
the news?
Okay. This was 2025. There's no news of
late.
So I don't know if it's top secret. Is
it a nuclear site? It's saying it's a
it's a
airport.
But look, Dimona is is in a desert.
Everyone can see it on a map. I can show
you on the map right now. The Mona if
you want. Let's do that because why not?
So the negative nuclear plant near the
ma is what we're talking about.
So this is Israel. It's near Ber Shiva.
And here we have Duna.
And here you have the negative nucle
nuclear research center.
Okay. And here you can see the reactor
dome and all that. So this is obviously
it used to be a secret facility. Now
everyone knows about it. Okay.
Uh because an an Israeli
whistleblower
alerted the world about this site.
Um David Crossman
uh Mora Morai Wanunu that guy. So this
nuclear research center is clearly out
there in the desert. Clearly Iran can
target it if they want. I suppose the
Israelis would have kept a separate
stockpile of interceptor missiles just
for this nuclear power plant. I'm sure
they will have done done that. So they
can do it theoretically
and uh they may possibly even do that in
the future. So no question about that
that obviously I am in agreement with
that. It's possible.
Abishek Shivastav says where is China in
this conflict? Where is China in this
conflict? China is playing a very
interesting and important role in this
conflict.
See, Iran is targeting its uh
adversaries with drones and with
missiles, right? And these strikes,
whether it's drone strikes or missile
strikes are very accurate, very
accurate. Now, how are the Iranians
doing this without GPS?
They're using the Chinese BU system.
China is providing is Iran with BU
because GPS is American. America will
switch off GPS for the Iranian region.
So the Iranians are using BU and that's
why China is in the conflict and China
obviously is gaining from the conflict.
The American stockpiles of arms,
weapons, munitions, everything is
beginning to run low and that obviously
is advantageous for China as well.
Dilshar says, "Love from Sydney. Thanks
for all the info. Thank you so much
indeed. Thank you so much.
Uh Pratt Dhan says, "It seems government
though Iran will not survive."
It seems government though Iran, you
mean the Iranian government wants to
survive. The Iranian government has been
taken out, right? It's been decapitated.
The top leadership, top 50 people or
whatever have been assassinated by the
Americans and still Iran is functioning.
Uh we'll see what happens. We'll see.
Iran is pretty prepared to fight mosaic
warfare, which means 31 independent
armies
and the Americans are going to go after
Iran. Obviously,
they may try and decapitate whichever
new leadership emerges. So, we'll see
about that. We'll see about that. I
think Iran is going to be resilient and
even if the Americans keep taking out
whatever leadership they have that it's
not actually a bad thing for a country
you know it ensures that that fresh
young blood rises to the top
it it solves the problem of elite over
production.
Amisha Mishra says
war how long will the war last? uh could
last months, possibly even years unless
the Americans are able to somehow defeat
Iran militarily. Now, since they are
now, you know, working on pushing
Kurdish militias into Iran, possibly
even have
maybe ISIS coming into Iran through
Syria or whatever and Iraq because the
Americans control Syria and Iraq, at
least parts of Iraq at least. So because
the Americans are now going for a plan
B, plan C, it it tells you that the plan
A hasn't worked.
So it looks like this war could last for
months, possibly even years.
Ritik Yadwanchi says Christopher Lando,
the American Deputy Secretary of State,
said the quiet part out loud just like
their orange man uh not extend uh same
unrescrocated economic advantages to
India it once gave to China. Yeah. Like
we discussed, how can India navigate?
Well, India can navigate. India has to
stop being a godamned lowquality nation.
The Indian elite need see the the rent
seeking model in India will not work.
India has to reform itself otherwise
India becomes a vasal. India has to
reform tremendously. There still is
time.
See what do you need in a nation to
survive these things. You need cohesion.
You need high energy in a nation. You
need a national mission. You need big
goals,
right? How do you make a nation
cohesive?
And and what else do you need? You need
the elimination of the internal threats.
So what should happen? First of all,
India should deport the whatever
millions of Bangladesh we have in India.
Whether it's 30 million, 50 million, 100
million, India needs to deport these
foreigners who are squatting in India
illegally. Whether it is the Rohhingas,
whether it is the Bangladeshes, whether
it is the cookies, whether it is
Pakistanis, all the illegals need to be
deported.
Secondly, India needs to make bring the
nation together instead of having
government policies that further divide
Indians.
All these cast based policies and
oppressor oppressed politics and all
that nonsense
that needs to go.
Third, the entire energy of India needs
to be channeled in in in the right
direction. India needs to reform its
manufacturing sector. India needs to
make it really genuinely easy to do
business in India. Cut down all the red
tape, all the nonsense. It means
reforms. India needs reforms and
education reforms also are needed. But
that will take a long time. So I'll not
discuss that even over here. And India
needs to militarize. India needs to
learn the lessons of the Iran war.
India needs massive stockpiles of
missiles and drones.
India needs sea power. India needs
submarines.
More than aircraft, missiles and drones
are what India needs. How many ballistic
missiles does India have? The AGN
missiles and what not Priti but mainly
the Agni missiles, right? How many does
India have?
India use India thinks of ballistic
missiles as the carrier of India's
nuclear deterrent. Which means if India
launches a ballistic missile, it means
India is launching launching a nuke. But
ballistic missiles can be used for for
for
conventional purposes as well.
So I think I'm not sure how many
ballistic missiles India even has. I
don't know 500. I have no idea. Iran has
more than 10,000 ballistic missiles it
looks like and more than 100,000 drones.
So India needs to build up a massive
stockpile of all kinds of missiles
whether it's cruise missiles,
supersonics, hypersonics, ballistic
missiles. If India gets into a war with
China for whatever reason, the Chinese
cities are thousands of kilometers away
and the Chinese industrial areas and
manufacturing centers uh and military
centers are thousands of kilometers
away.
How how are you going to target them?
You're going to need ballistic missiles
for that. India seems to have not
thought of this at all. So a lot needs
to be done. How do we navigate the US
challenge but we can't keep on bowing
down to the Americans and bending to
their will and giving them whatever
trade deal they want and whatever they
ask of India. Stop buying oil from here
or there or whatever.
India needs to sit straight up and grow
spine and for that India needs to reform
itself so that it can grow economically.
whether the Americans cooperate or not
and obviously they will use leverage
against us the leverage translates
eventually into military capabilities
so India needs to militarize India needs
to get become really really powerful
militarily way more than what it is
today and you don't wait for your GDP to
grow for the military growth military to
grow you can allocate 5% of your GDP for
the next 10 years to military to to to
defense in offense instead of whatever
it is right now. So India needs to
really change really transform itself
really reform itself over the next 3 to
5 years actually beginning beginning
today. That way we can navigate
otherwise we are destined to be an
American basal. So even now there's a
very high chance that in the within the
next 5 years India becomes an American
basal. I hope it doesn't happen. I I
don't want it to happen. I'm just
telling you that it's quite possible.
India still can navigate. India still
can can remain fully sovereign.
So that's what India needs to do.
Okay. DRMPC
says I am surprised to hear you say in
Vad that we were threatened by operation
by US to oper.
What are you talking about?
I'm surprised to hear you say Vad. Vad
is a podcast. I have never been to Vad.
What are you talking about, sir?
When have I been to Vad? I may have said
elsewhere that the Americans forced us
to end operations. Were you surprised
about it? Well, then grow the hell up.
If you're surprised about this,
grow up. That's the only thing I can
tell you.
Does it hurt your feelings? What I said?
Do facts hurt your feelings? Please grow
up, sir. Please or ma'am, please grow
up.
Um, aren't we going to use one of our
swam survi in government? I think Indian
the Indian government is going to use
chat GPT
which makes us a full-fledged vasal
state if that is operationalized.
Aam Senpai says Iran improved missile
accuracy significantly switching from
GPS to Chinese BU.
Russia providing Iran real-time location
data of US military assets. Yes, all of
this is happening. Russia and China are
both helping Iran in this indirect
manner.
So Iran has switched from GPS to BO. GPS
won't be available to them anymore
because it's an American system and the
BO system seems to be really great. So
Indians like to make fun of China,
right? The Chinese missiles aren't good,
Chinese radars aren't good and so on.
Well, here you have an example of
Chinese excellence. The Iranians are
using Chinese BU and they are getting
great results. As a consequence,
the ch there are Chinese military
satellites, reconnaissance satellites
that are also providing Iran with real
almost realtime information, data,
images and so on of American military
assets and deployments and so on. Uh the
Russians are also involved in some way
or the other, right?
That's another lesson for India to
learn. India's Navic or whatever system
it is, the satellite navigation system,
it's almost defunct right now. That's
what one hears. We only have limited
coverage of the subcontinent, not global
coverage like the Russians and the
Chinese. We only have modest ambitions
of limited surveillance capabilities in
the subcontinent. Even that is not
working fine. India has totally dropped
the ball in space.
India needs to have its own
alternative to the GPS which is not
local but global.
It doesn't even cost a lot of money. I
don't know why the government of India
is not planning in these directions.
Ritik says why is Russia an ally of Iran
just like China?
Well, that's a good fundamental question
because the US is opposed to Russia,
it's opposed to China, it's opposed to
Iran. Okay? So, when the Americans, the
superpower, the empire are opposed to
three nations, they will obviously want
to band together. So, it's obviously
much more complicated and than that. But
overall, their interests converge. They
have shared interests. Russia, Iran,
China, North Korea. These four nations
have shared interests and they seek to
remain sovereign.
That's why
Kakashi says divisive and fraudulent
leftright spectrum should not be
imported into bat from the west. There
should just be pro- national
civilization versus antinational. Well,
this leftright
terminology has become fully mainstream
in India.
if we if it should not have been
imported but it happened a long time ago
now it's just part of the mainstream
discourse
but I agree with you I agree with what
you're saying the the actual perspective
is whether you are pro pro- nation and
civilization or anti-nation and
civilization that is the correct way of
looking at things but we tend to look at
it look at things from right left
perspective right winger left winger all
that stuff it's actually pro- nation
pro- civilization and anti-nation
anti-vilivilization I completely
completely agree with you. Completely
agree with you.
Kauashi says in many places like South
America and Japan, it is the left wing
that is against vasilization and the
sale of their nation. Both right-wing
and leftwing can be both bought. You
see, right-wing and leftwing are people.
People
most people can be bought.
Every person most persons will have some
right price
and when you are the most powerful and
wealthiest country in the world it's not
that difficult to to buy out somebody
whether they are right-wing or leftwing
doesn't make any difference whoever is
in power get them to work for you right
so yeah that is correct that's correct
music man says why is no one talking
about the babal Al Babal Mandabra as an
alternative for Saudi Gulf countries to
export oil. It's a is it is this a
feasible option or impossible? Okay, let
us go to map.
It's the Bab al- Mandeb straight. Okay,
so we have the straight of Hormos here
which is a very important geographical
choke point. And there's another one
here which is the Bab al-Mandde
straight, the straight of tears.
Bab al-Mande straight. So the question
is why can't these nations okay um
export oil through the Bab al-mandib
strait. So tell me something. The UAE is
a major oil exporter. H it's sitting up
north here. The distance from the UAE to
let's say the Red Sea is about 1250
kilometers. How will the UAE transport
oil through this massive desert? Look at
the desert. Can you see? It's just sand
dunes. It's just desert.
Just desert.
Massive, massive sand dunes.
Nothing else here for hundreds and
thousands of kilometers. How does the
UAE do that? How does Oman do that?
And Oman anyway is in on this part of
the this side of the world. So they are
fine,
right? And when it comes to Bab al-
Mandeb, you have Yemen sitting here
which is pro- Iran, which is an Iranian
ally and that's why and the people of
Yemen have been there's been a war waged
against them by the Americans, the
Saudis and other countries in the region
and why will Yemen cooperate? They won't
cooperate. And even if you bypass Yemen
go through this region Saudi Arabia it's
more than more than 1200 kilometers that
you have to transport the oil. How do
you do it? Through trucks through
aircraft you build a pipeline that takes
years.
If you are Kuwait how do you access
Babal Mandrid? It's too far. If you're
Iraq once again it's the same problem
distance through desert. So it's an
alternative on paper. On paper you can
draw a line but in the real world you
can't draw a line like you would draw in
paper. Right
in Phoenix says from what we see using
game theory from what we see using game
theory and for curiosity who is firing
nuclear missile nobody has fired nuclear
missile
nobody has done it right who is firing
nobody's firing nobody's firing both if
pushed to the brink what will happen as
hormones controls food for GCC and oil
for for Asia
Um,
who is firing nuclear missiles? See,
first of all, nobody is firing nuclear
missiles. Maybe you're trying to ask who
may fire a nuclear missile. Is that what
you're trying to ask actually? Well,
then you can use different words, I
suppose, to to actually accurately mean
what you say. Who may fire nuclear
missiles? Look, Iran, as far as we know,
don't doesn't have nuclear weapons as
far as we know.
In case they have nuclear weapons, if
they if they are pushed against the
wall, they may perhaps use those nuclear
weapons. Israel, well, if Israel takes
too much damage, they may use nuclear
weapons.
Right now, there's a tremendous amount
of damage apparently that Tel Aiv and
Hifi and other other cities are
apparently taking. So, if the damage
becomes unbearable, intolerable, Israel
may be tempted to use nuclear weapons.
If Trump gets desperate that Iran is not
falling, he may possibly use nuclear
weapons. Yeah, these are the three
possibilities. Israel, the US and Iran,
all three may use nuclear weapons. Is
Iran if they have it? So in case
hypothetically Iran has nuclear weapons,
they may use nukes
if nukes are used against them or if
their their very existence is threatened
as a sovereign nation. In that case,
Iran may use nukes. Israel may use nukes
if if it takes too much damage, like
unbearable, intolerable damage. And the
US may use nukes if if Trump wakes up on
the wrong side of the bed.
Uh KDSI says, "What's the likelihood of
the US going nuclear?" Right now, it's
low. Right now, the likelihood of the US
going nuclear is low. But if this war
continues and the US takes more and more
damage and the US uh
US plan B also doesn't work using Kuresh
and ISIS militias Kuresh militias and
ISIS terrorists if that doesn't work
if Israel takes a lot of damage
if Trump's political position becomes
very weak
see if this continues okay if this war
continues and if Iran is not defeated
then the Republicans will be wiped out
in the midterm elections in November.
That is obviously intolerable to Trump.
So depending on all all these things and
how dangerous the situation is for
Trump, he may possibly decide to use
nuclear weapons against Iran. And I'll
tell you what, even if he does use
nuclear weapons against Iran, Iran is
going to keep fighting. So
minimalist Maverick's trajectory of
Pakistan Afghan proxy war Indian
involvement there is no Indian
involvement in Pakistan Afghanistan is
not a proxy war it's a direct war it's a
direct war there's no proxy in between
it's not a proxy war
so the trajectory yeah I don't know it's
going to continue
uh the Afghans call the Duran line the
imaginary border which means that they
don't accept the duran line as the
border between Afghanistan and Pakistan.
And this is going to go on.
Afghanistan isn't like a very powerfully
armed nation. It doesn't have a massive
military.
It depends on the US.
The US pays Afghanistan a weekly stipend
of anything between 30 to $100 million
in cash.
Obviously, the US needs Afghanistan for
something. that may change possibly
given the changing circumstances or
maybe that you know Afghanistan become
may become even more important for the
US
because the US stops paying Afghanistan
maybe China steps in
yeah that won't be acceptable to the
Americans so they need to keep paying
Afghanistan
so I think this war between Afghanistan
Pakistan could also go on for a long
time hopefully not but it looks like
that there is no Indian involvement
Rumit Mishra says if India becomes a US
vasal will that impact India's cavary
jet engine program or the other defense
project that India is currently working
on. If you become a vasal of a foreign
nation your projects don't matter
anymore.
Even if you build jet engines and high
technology they'll be used by the
overlord not by you. they'll be
appropriated for their benefit. So how
does it matter
if India becomes the US vasile? Neither
the cavary jet engine program will
matter nor the submarine programs may
matter nor anything will matter. Once
you are a vasal you are a slave. You may
not look like a slave. Most people will
not realize also you are a slave but
you're a slave. Your destiny will be in
their hands. They may allow you to
continue the cover jet engine program.
They may even give you the technology as
long as you are under their control. It
doesn't matter anymore once you are a
vasal.
Aries Manticor says the US is trying to
reduce embarrassment by claiming that
they have given wavers and that Indians
are good actors. By the way, we have
never stopped purchasing Russian oil and
when the war broke out, we immediately
pivoted back without US permission.
Uh we have not stopped purchasing
Russian oil. That is correct.
There were claims being made that India
had stopped purchasing Russian oil and
India did not bother to refute those
claims.
India did reduce
its uh
its consumption of Russian oil but never
stopped it.
And uh once the war broke out, we had no
cho no choice but to ramp up our import
of Russian oil and we did not bother to
take any so-called permission from from
the US for that. So I totally agree with
you over here. Uh maybe the Americans
are are trying to you know save face.
Okay. Sumit Suman says professor Jang is
suddenly promoted everywhere. Is someone
pushing a certain narrative? You've also
noticed something. Please hint so
viewers can avoid blind faith. I have
noticed that professor Jang is being
promoted on YouTube. He's suddenly all
over YouTube, isn't he?
So now, Professor Jang is claiming that
America will lose this war against Iran.
If that's the case, why is YouTube
promoting this person?
That's a question that I don't have an
answer to right now, but something is
fishy clearly. Why are the Americans
promoting this this gentleman on an
American platform? Shouldn't they
suppress his his voice and his reach
algorithmically?
I I wonder.
So, I'm not sure what the deal is. I
haven't watched his I mean I mean I
watched one or two snippets of his
videos. Sounds like a competent and
intelligent person who knows what he's
talking about. But I haven't seen his
long videos to figure out whether
there's some some hidden narrative that
is being being inserted in in his
videos. I can't say no don't not have
the time to watch hour long videos.
Right? So I don't know but one has to be
careful.
Nirmala Sharma says hey why don't you
count France in the sovereign nation
list? Don't they operate they don't
operate US jets and air defense and even
radars and are pro- sovereign Europe?
Okay, good question and I've explained
it a 100 times but I will do it one more
time because you may be a new viewer so
I understand. See,
sovereignty is not some imaginary
concept that I have dreamt up.
Sovereignty is very real. What are the
components of sovereignty?
There is territorial sovereignty.
There is economic sovereignty. There is
military sovereignty.
There is legislative and policy
sovereignty.
There is technological sovereignty.
There is energy sovereignty. Now let's
consider two or three of these factors.
Territorial sovereignty. Territorial
sovereignty means you completely control
your nation's borders and you decide who
comes in and who can't come in.
Does France have territorial
sovereignty?
France is a member of the EU.
As a member of the EU, it can't stop
other me citizens from other EU nations
from coming in.
So France doesn't have territorial
sovereignty. Anybody from any EU nation
has the right to come into France.
So none of the EU nations are have
territorial sovereignty. That
territorial sovereignty score is zero.
Second
economic sovereignty which means you
control your economy.
You have your own national bank and you
control your own economy and your own
currency.
Does France have its own currency?
No,
France has to use the euro. This common
currency of the European Union. If you
don't have your currency, you don't have
economic sovereignty.
Third, military sovereignty. France is a
member of NATO.
What is military sovereignty? Military
sovereignty means you control your
military. As a member of NATO,
France will be in situations at various
points in time every year where at least
some portion of its military come under
comes under the command of a foreigner.
So France doesn't have military
sovereignty. So France doesn't have
doesn't have territorial sovereignty. It
doesn't have economic sovereignty. It
doesn't have military sovereignty. So
that's why I don't count France as a
fully sovereign nation. But I'll say
this, among the EU and NATO nations,
France is the most sovereign of all of
those. All right. I hope that makes
sense. Yeah. Okay. At Misha says, "In
Risina summit, US was bullying us. When
does the US not bully other nations?"
When does the US not bully other
nations? in any such summit
or whatever the US never misses a chance
to bully other nations and especially
India.
So the US was bullying us in the risina
summit. Okay. India buying Suko 57 will
be a key nexus defending our
sovereignty. Kindly reiterate your five
points for taking things forward for PM
next PM hopefully Yogi. I don't remember
which five points I have said earlier
but look we have to learn the lessons
from uh the Iran war.
Why is Iran able to survive as a
sovereign nation? Because it is very
powerful
militarily especially in drones and
missiles. Maybe its navy isn't great.
Maybe the Americans have destroyed the
navy. Maybe the air force is second
rate. The Americans have destroyed the
air force also. But when it comes to
missiles and drones, they are first
rate. They are better than the Americans
and they have got tremendous quantities
of weapons. Those weapons quantity has a
quality of its own. You must have heard
this from me since at least 2021.
Right? So India needs to do these
things. India needs to militarize. India
needs to stop allocating like 1 or 2% or
whatever of its GDP to to the military.
Maybe it's time to allocate 5% of GDP to
the to the military next 10 years.
and Indian needs to reform and all those
things like I said earlier right all
those things need to be done for next
prime minister hopefully Yogi will I'll
stay out of Indian politics I don't
comment about that
obviously I have my own views about this
but I don't I don't talk about that in
in these forums I stay out of politics
domestic politics
general subutaya says why Russia not
resupplying Iran US invades India
potential Iran style outcome India skips
Pakistan invasion due to oil.
If you don't have sufficient oil, you
can't fight a war. By the way, so people
who are saying we should resume
operation sindur,
calm down.
Okay,
those of us who want to resume operation
Sindur, where's the oil? India allegedly
has 25 days of oil supplies or strategic
oil reserves. That's what media is
reporting. I don't know how true or
false that is. Some some people are
saying that's false or whatever. But
see, when there's an oil crisis, you
can't go to war.
You can go to war, but in that case, you
to finish the war very fast.
So that why is Russia not resupplying
Iran? Russia is helping Iran in other
ways. And if Iran needs resupplying,
Russia will do that. Okay. Not right
now. If US invades India, potentially
Iran style style outcome.
Does India have 10,000 ballistic
missiles? India doesn't have 10,000
ballistic ballistic missiles. India may
have several thousand cruise missiles
including Brahos and so on.
But we need all kinds of assets and I
don't think India has 100,000 plus
drones.
So India is kind of short on these
things. The way I see it, I may be
completely wrong. I hope I am. But that
gives us an opportunity in case I'm
right that India should now stockpile
tens of thousands of ballistic missiles
and hundreds of thousands of drones and
possibly tens of thousands of cruise
missiles too. If you have that, nobody
will dare come to you, especially if
you're a nuclear weapon state. Okay.
Prataradana says, "At least one good
news. Our own air independent propulsion
system is installed in a submarine."
Well, that it's it's going to be
installed in a submarine. So, India has
developed apparently an indigenous air
independent propulsion system. That's
fantastic.
And it's going to be installed in
submarines. So, let's see the news.
AIP submarines.
Um, India is retrofitting its calvari
class corpine submarines with
indigenously developed AIP systems. Uh
when does this happen? It's a video.
So it enables diesel electric submarines
to remain underwater for 14 to uh 91
days 14 to 21 days compared to only 2 3
days without it. So it's excellent.
Excellent.
And so on. Yeah. So
Oh, I have the map on the screen instead
of this. Okay.
So yeah, India is retrofitting its
Kalvari or Scorp scorpion submarines
with indigenously developed AIP systems
and AIP system enables diesel electric
submarines to operate underwater for 14
to 21 days as compared to only 2 to 3
days without it. So that's fantastic,
isn't it? Uh
okay. So yeah, excellent. It's it's a
great piece of news clearly.
Mihir says,
"Just wanted to point something out. A
look at JP Morgan Asset Management's
global manufacturing PMI index report
comparison
since 2009 2026. You want me to look
into that? Let's see. Uh, give me a
second.
I'll
Okay, let us put this on the screen.
And you want to see JP Morgan JP Morg
let's see
JP Morgan asset management's global
manufacturing PMI index report
comparison 2009 to 2026.
Um,
okay. What do you want me to see in
this?
Um,
I'm not sure what you're trying to point
out over here. Um, India, the India
factor. What is it? Okay. Anyway, thank
you.
Next question.
Bashupati Johi says,
"Hope you're doing great." Yes, I'm
doing great. How are you? I hope you're
doing great, too. Iran has been
attacking data service, data center
servers in GCC countries. Why? And at
whose behest? China are data centers
there used by American bases in the
region more than MNC companies.
Uh the Gulf nations have data centers
there. data centers
are part of the cloud services that are
offered across the world. So one example
is Amazon Web Services the cloud right.
So what happens is that you have if you
are if you are a customer and you have
your data on the cloud that data is
stored in multiple places not just on
one server but multiple servers. So if
you are let's say tomorrow morning going
to be in New York City then you can
access your data from the nearest server
which will be typically based in the US.
But if you are going to be in India you
will want to access your data from a
local server if if AW has a service in
India you'll access it from there or
maybe a nearby place like Singapore or
UAE or whatever.
So that's how it's done. That's data
centers. So Iran has been attacking data
centers but that is a critical
vulnerability of the of cloud services.
Uh these are not used by only by
American bases. They are used they
probably used by MNC's not by American
bases. The American bases will have
their own the American military will
have its own data centers which will be
separate from uh the data centers used
by MNC's multinational corporations.
So if Iran attacks and destroys data
centers, it's it's exposing a critical
vulnerability of the US.
It's not doing it at somebody's behest.
It's a great strategy. If you are being
if you're under attack, you attack every
aspect of the of the of the adversaries
operations,
right?
Your objective is to impose a very high
price on the adversary, a very high cost
on the adversary, a cost for their
actions. Since you are attacking me, I'm
going to make it very costly for you,
right? I'm going to make you pay a very
heavy price. And that's by doing all
these things. So if you attack data data
centers, maybe a company's data is is
stored in two data centers and one is
gone. Now what happens?
Right. So it's not being done at China's
behest or Russia's beh
it's it's a logical
strategic
maneuver by Iran.
AL BJ says DY KDU do you know about
offshore
offshore gas and oil exploration column
coast? I'm not aware of it. I'm not
aware of it. Is something happening?
That'll be great.
Ritik Yadu Wshi says, "How close would
have would an American submarine have
been to India in the Indian Ocean when
they launched the torpedo at the Iranian
ship?" Um, it happened south of Gal,
right? Gal Gal, what's the
pronunciation? I don't know. Let's call
it Gaul. So, if you go to the map,
if you go to the map here, we have Sri
Lanka. This is the city of Gaul. Okay?
And this incident this this uh sinking
of the Iranian ship happened south of
Gal. So it means that let's say it
happened in this location where I put a
dot here. If you calculate the distance
to Kanyakamari it's about 300 400 km.
So the American submarine would have
been about 3 400 maybe around 400
kilometers away from Indian India's
coast when they launched that the
torpedo at the Iranian ship. But these
American submarines
are pretty undetectable. I don't know if
the Indian Navy would have known it was
there. Hopefully they would have known
but it's possible they may not have
known because first of all it was
outside of Indian territorial waters in
India's exclusive economic zone.
So I hope that now people are
understanding how important submarines
are and how vulnerable aircraft carriers
are. The Americans are hiding their
aircraft carriers far away from Iran.
But submarines can sneak up to you and
kill you. Submarines are the dangerous
most dangerous ship
naval asset in the world. Aircraft
carriers are a liability.
Parasur says, "Does the US lack intent
or does it lack capability to defend the
Gulf countries as it certainly wants to
defend Israel but is unable to defend
it?"
I think the US primarily
focuses on Israel. So if if if they are
given an option of saving Israel or
saving another country in the region,
they will go for Israel first. They will
save Israel first, then they will
prioritize other countries. So priority
wise, Israel is number one for the US.
But the US is not able to safeguard I
mean defend Israel right now, right?
Israel is taking
hits from from Iranian drones and
missiles. So even if the Americans do
want to
protect Israel, they are not able to.
Uh so it's it's a combination of both
when it comes to the Gulf countries. U
the the Americans prioritize Israel
higher than the Gulf countries and the
American military infrastructure has
most likely been severely compromised in
this region. So they're unable to defend
the Gulf countries even if they want to.
And the question is
even when the American military
infrastructure was intact,
was it enough to defend the Gulf
countries? Probably it was not enough.
Probably it was not enough.
Tutin says, "Have you seen the video of
American Marine veteran being man
handled in the US Senate from for saying
no one wants to fight for Israel?" Looks
like Mir Shamar was right. I have seen
that video and uh his arm was broken,
right? His forearm was broken. You could
hear the bones cracking. He could you
could see the bone shards poking out of
his shirt
of his jacket. Yeah, I've seen that. And
he was shouting that we don't want to we
we don't want to fight and die for
Israel or something to that effect. Uh
yeah, I've seen that. I am not sure what
Mir Framer has said about this, but I
have indeed seen that video. Yeah,
Ryik P says, "Do you believe we have a
competent MEA, Ministry of External
Affairs to handle once in a century
geopolitical changes?" One wrong move
and uh yeah, it's disaster. In my
opinion, it looks like we are making a
wrong move.
So, in your opinion, if you think we are
making a wrong move, could you kindly
help me understand what wrong? What
wrong move are we making?
I think India is trying its best to
navigate the situation the best way it
can. Um,
do we have a competent
ministry of external affairs or minister
Minister of External Affairs?
I think he's he's what we have. I think
he's a very experienced uh diplomat
with decades of experience. I think he
probably is one of the best people we
probably have. I'm sure there are other
diplomats who could take up the role but
I'm not sure about that. Dr. Jashankar
has the experience and so on. Competent.
I'm sure he's competent.
Um and at the end of the day the moves
that we make are not made by the
ministry minister of external affairs.
They made by the prime minister.
The minister simply communicates
and interfaces with other countries.
Um, I think we are doing our best to to
handle these treacherous times.
We don't want to antagonize the US
verbally too much, but we want to have
as many options as possible and remain
as uh strategically autonomous as
possible.
When it when it comes to me being
frustrated with the Indian with India,
it's not my frustration doesn't come
from the Ministry of External Affairs.
My frustration comes from the lack of
reforms in India which are vital which
are critical which are indispensable for
India remaining sovereign. I mean is it
difficult to to to deport a few million
Bangladesh? Is it impos is it is it
impossible? Is it so hard? Why can't
that be done? So that's what frustrates
me. The MEA is fine.
Mr. Sid is a new member. Thank you very
much. Mr. Sid, welcome to the channel
and thank you so much. Here is Manticor
says as you see the US itself is showing
itself to be a terrible overlord if
India chooses them. Of course I think
the Indian government will no longer
choose them. It will be open season on
the US slowly soon. Five pyear race is
on.
See it's not like India has to make a
choice.
Be sovereign or choose the US. Which is
best? When somebody wants to vasalize
you, you don't they don't leave you with
much choice, right?
When the US government, let's say, has a
tremendous amount of leverage on you,
economic leverage, military leverage,
other kinds of leverage,
then you may have no choice.
It's it's like
it's like saying that hypothetically
that you can choose to be rich or poor.
What shall you choose? Everybody will
choose to be rich, right? But being rich
is very difficult. That's the situation.
Nobody chooses to be poor. People are
poor because they don't know how to be
rich.
So it's not like India will okay now
tomorrow will wake up and say, "Oh no,
that's not true to be a vasal." No, when
you are being vasalized, you are always
being vasalized against your wishes.
It's a forcible imposition upon you. So
the US is a terrible overlord. We know
that.
And sometimes even if you try your best
you get vosilized. I mean was was Japan
a nation that chose vasilization? They
were nuked into vasilization right.
Um but hopefully the the Indian
government makes the right decisions and
and the right moves that enables it it
to remain independent and sovereign. But
yeah, the longer this war drags on and
the longer Iran remains resilient and
sovereign,
the lower America's credibility will
will go and everybody will look for
options. So that I agree completely.
P Gorpad says for India is the biggest
risk from this war oil supply, diaspora
safety or diplomatic balance. Number one
is oil supply.
diplomatic balance. We can always do
diplomatic balancing that is fine.
Diaspora is safe. The Iranians aren't
targeting civilians right in the Gulf
countries. I don't think India has much
of a diaspora Israel.
And so the diaspora is mostly safe.
Diplomatic balance we can anyway
maintain.
The biggest risk from the war is the oil
supply. That's the biggest risk factor
for India.
Yeah. So that's the biggest risk.
We lo says, "Have you read the code
breakers by David Khan?" I've heard of
it, but I haven't read it.
Probably don't have it either. So, no, I
haven't.
The Priya says, "Bhat still guarding one
Iranian warship. Iran thanks." Why?
Because why not?
Because we are a sovereign nation and
Iran is not our enemy.
Iran with Iran we have good relations so
if a nation who is not your enemy and
with whom you've had good relations if
they request you that please safeguard
our warship for the time being why will
you not not accept the request
unless you are somebody's vasal
so India is now you could say
reccalibrating
initially
when the war happened India condemned
the uh attack on various nation
sovereignty without naming Iran in India
did not um
offer condolences to the people of Iran
over the assassination of their supreme
leader but now India is changing course
and I think it's the right thing to do
right so it's it's it's a statement it's
a it's an assertion of India's
sovereignty it's also a message to the
US
that uh you know we are a sovereign
nation and we will not
bow down to you.
Aris Manticor says THA terminal high
altitude area defense has been
obliterated by the Iranian forces.
That's what it looks like. Uh definitely
the uh radar
systems at least a couple of these seem
to have been obliterated by Iran. Yeah,
Jose, thank you very much sir. Thank you
very much indeed. Thank you.
Lucky Mahara says, "Sergy, will India
give our ports to the US in this war if
the time comes? Can we say no to them?"
So there have
been speculations and claims by American
commentators that the US is currently
using Indian ports
and the Indian government has stated
very clearly the Americans are not using
Indian ports. We have not given anybody
permission to use Indian ports.
Okay. So I can say this for sure right
now that the US Navy and military
is not using Indian ports. But the
question is in the future what happens?
You can see the uh
the American fifth fleet, a very major
naval fleet was based in uh Bahrain
and it looks like their military
infrastructure has been dismantled by
the by the Iranians, destroyed by the
Iranians and American naval warships
can't operate in the Persian Gulf or the
Hormuz region because Iran will take
them take them out. So there's an
aircraft carrier strike group in the
eastern Mediterranean more than a
thousand kilometers from Iran and
there's an aircraft carrier strike group
in the Arabian Sea, southern Arabian
Sea. Again, they are distancing
themselves. They're putting distance
between them and Iran. So in that case,
if they want to operate aircraft
carriers, destroyers, warships,
submarines in the region, submarines,
they may be all nuclear powered. That's
fine. No need for refueling. But other
warships will need refueling
and restocking. So where will they do
it? The Gulf region is unstable. If
there's an American warship there, it
can be targeted and destroyed by the
Iranians. So where do the Americans
dock? Let's take a look at the map.
See,
if you have an American warship in the
Persian Gulf, it will be destroyed by
the Iranians.
At least it'll be targeted by the
Iranians. And the Iranians know how to
It's very clear now the Iranians know
how to destroy uh military assets. So
it's it doesn't make sense for American
warships to be in this region over here.
Gulf of Oman again too close to Iran,
too dangerous. So the American aircraft
carrier must be like a few hundred
kilometers from Iran at least. Okay.
Maybe south of south of Pakistan.
If you have American warships in Oman,
the Iranians can take those out. Yemen,
impossible. Yemen is not friendly
friendly to the US. Saudi Arabia, Red
Sea, well that's too far anyway, right?
And then you have the eastern
Mediterranean which is again very far.
So if the Americans want to engage in
naval warfare they will need to have
their ships resupplied with fuel fuel
and other things. Where do they do it?
One possibility is Guadada Pakistan.
But if the Americans are resupplied from
Guadada, the Iranians can take out
Guadar. Iran is right next door.
Or you could have Karachi.
Well the Iranians could target Karachi
as well. Karachi is not that far away.
Right? So then what? India. The other
option is India. Then that's why I say
that it's likely the Americans may
demand
that India gave access to its ports
that India allow American warships to
use Indian ports.
But that makes that if that happens if
India agrees to that it makes India an
accessory in the war. So India will not
accept that.
Okay. And the Americans will try to
pressurize India, arm twist India,
whatever.
What should India do? India should
refuse.
That's it.
And I'm sure we can say no to them. We
may have to pay some price for it, but
I'm sure we will be able to say no to
the Americans. If this war continues a
few more weeks, few more months, the
Americans will need will ask for Indian
pause and we have to say no.
Jose Shik says, "What can the government
how can the government change the
mindset of Indians who blindly take
sides in foreign wars without knowing
actually what's in our interest?"
What the government can do is it can
reform the education system so that so
that Indians actually understand what
the national interest is and what the
Indian national interest is because
every nation has its own
national interest set of national
interests which are different from the
interests of other nations. So the
government of India it can change the
mindset of Indians to do that it has to
reform the education system and bring
and and ensure that these topics are
taught because they are vital they're
critical
that's how you if you're taught these
things when you're in school
then you'll genuinely understand the
world
and nobody will be able to fool you as a
citizen. So it has to be done in the
education system. Right now those who
are grown up the whatever is in their
mind you can't change. After a certain
period after a certain age most people
can't change their minds.
That age may be around 40. Most people
after the age of 40 they simply will
refuse to change their mind about
something they believe.
And many people even younger ages don't
can't change their mind or can't can't
think clearly. So you have to inculcate
these things during a young age. For
that you have to reform the education
system. Otherwise the government can't
change the mindset of Indians. That
slave mentality, that inferiority
complex, that hero worshiing other
countries and all it's because of the
defective education system. That is what
needs to change. That's how you create a
highquality population.
Mihir says, "What's your objective
viewpoint on channels like digging into
China, China observer le China insider
DI Jang? They seem to be fallen
gongfunded. I haven't seen any of the
channels.
I have no idea. I haven't watched any of
these channels." Sorry.
Shuham Shuham Chipped says, "Will all EU
unwillingly enter the war on the US
side?" Look, the EU is already exhausted
when it comes to the Ukraine war. I'm
sure they don't want to enter this war.
The EU nations
um and EU nations
are not bound to enter into wars if the
Americans tell them. But NATO is a
different matter. NATO nations are
treaty bound to help each other in times
of whatever you know need and so on
based on the NATO charter
and an attack on one member of NATO is
to be considered as an attack on all
NATO members. So does it mean that NATO
nations should participate in the war
because Iran is attacking the US? Well,
Iran is not attacking the US. Iran is
defending itself. The US doesn't exist
in the Middle East, right? The US is a
North America.
uh Iran may be attacking American bases
but because that's because the bases
American bases attacked Iran first. So
Iran is simply defending itself. So that
doesn't trigger article 5. Yeah. You
can't do these mental gymnastics to uh
trigger article 5 of NATO
because of the uh war in the in the Gulf
region. Um but the Americans may arm
twist individual NATO members like
Germany for example, maybe the UK, maybe
France or whoever to enter the war and
if the Americans want something they can
generally get their way when it comes to
the European nations, NATO nations. So
it is possible that if the war drags on,
you may see the entry of Germany or some
other nations, European nations in the
war
and that will be bad for Iran. If more
nations enter the war that will
certainly make it more likely that
Russia and China could enter the war or
in on Iran's side and that
becomes a world war right so
really now Mr. Patel says Aravvin means
urging saying that we buy US oil soon.
I'm telling you this guy
I don't know it's a guy girl whoever
it's an anonymous account
based in the US and yeah this is the
inserious little narrative this account
puts out and other accounts like these
so it's about this is a psychological
operation to when lots of people start
following you whatever you say matters
because it has an effect
and because he has acquired this
reputation for being able to accurately
predict the future which means actually
that he or she has inside information
right so then what you say will be
believed by people that it it will
actually happen and maybe it puts
pressure on the government of India
so this is a scop account it's probably
a CIA or American run SCOP account
Aravind
Shiraaki says how will this war affect
the Abraham Accords um
what are the Abraham Accords is about
peace between Israel and the West Asian
nations, right? It doesn't involve uh
Iran.
How will this war affect those Abraham
Accords? Let's first see in in brief
what the Abraham Accords are all about.
Abraham Accords,
okay,
US brokered joint peace declarations,
normalize relations between Israel and
several Arab nations
and so on.
Yeah, it doesn't really affect the
Abraham Accords too much.
Putting says operation on Ismile Khani
of IRGC. He looks like Kushal Bahra.
What?
Well, the Iranians are our cousins
anyway, right? So, there'll be Iranians
who look like us and us who some of us
who looks who look like them. Ismile
Khani of the IRGC. I have no opinion on
him. I have not studied his life
history, his career, his views. I I
don't know about him. Looks like Kushel
Mirror really.
Let's see. Let's see.
Ismile Khani. I RGC.
Ismile
Khani.
Uh
there are reports has been executed. I
don't know if if it's true. Maybe it's
rumors. Maybe it's psychological
warfare. Does it look like Kushell?
Maybe a little bit.
Okay. Rajie. Rajiv. Thank you so much.
Rajiv G. Thank you so much.
JRXna says
per the Mandro doctrine the US needs to
counter China by cutting cheap heavy oil
from Venezuela, cheap silver from Latin
America, cheap oil from Iran. Why is
China not reacting to the plan of
destruction?
I don't know what Donro doctrine is, but
I've heard of the Monro doctrine. The
Monro doctrine is about US supremacy
in the Western Hemisphere.
The Mando doctrine is an American policy
that dates back to 1823 or something.
And in its original form, it was that
the US, it was the US saying that no
European nation will be allowed to
influence
the politics or geopolitics
of the Americas, whether it's North
America, Central America or South
America. It means that European nations
who were the colonial nations of the
time, they were no longer allowed to
interfere in the internal matters of the
nations in the Americas.
That was the Mandro doctrine.
It's about American supremacy in the
western hemisphere.
Now the Mandro doctrine has been uh
reinstated by Trump and he has put forth
a Trump corollary or rider on top of it
which says that even among in the
Americas no nation whether it's north
south central America no nation will be
allowed to do any activities that in any
way hurt American interests if that
happens the Americans will go and deal
with it militarily if required that's
the Mundo doctrine and the Trump corery
so the Mundo doctrine has nothing to do
with Iran or China. It's about the
western hemisphere.
Okay? It's about only the western
hemisphere. But America's actions here
are see America has reinstated the Monro
doctrine when people were interpreting
that it was hemispheric retreat. It was
a retreat to hemispheric defense. But
that's not the case. The Americans are
expanding their activities in the
eastern hemisphere through their war on
Iran. Right?
So the war on Iran is about at the end
of the day about countering China, about
cutting off China's oil sources of oil
supply or controlling those and that's
what it is. Why is China not reacting to
their planned destruction? Well, China
has decent oil strategic oil reserves.
China can always always get oil from
Russia.
And China knows that if this war goes on
for a longer time, the Americans will
eventually have to either nuke Iran or
to withdraw and retreat, walk out. Once
that happens, the Chinese know that the
Gulf nations will never ever do business
with America again. They won't trust the
Americans again. The American military
presence in the region will be wiped
out. It may already be severely degraded
right now. The American military
facilities and bases in the region may
be severely degraded by now. So once the
Americans let's say move out of the
region if they are unable to defeat Iran
then the Gulf nations will no longer
want to do business with the Americans
they will prefer to do business with the
China with the Chinese and the Indians.
So China long-term benefits from this
and China is not being threatened right
now directly. Even if it's being
threatened because of oil supply being
cut off potentially there's nothing they
can do about it right now. That's why
they are staying out of it and they're
keeping a close eye on what's happening.
Noise is a new member. Thank you very
much. Noise. Welcome to the channel's
membership.
Anod Kumar says some advice you would
like to give to the next PM of India.
Reform. See, I am first of all nobody to
give advice to the prime minister of
India. But let's say I am to give
advice. I would say reform the country.
The rent seeeking model will not work
anymore. It it will work. But then India
becomes a vasile. It becomes a third
rate nation. It remains a third rate
nation. India needs to reform itself.
India needs to reform its institutions.
India needs to milit militar militarize
significantly maybe spend 3 to 5% of its
GDP on military expenditure for the next
10 years at least.
India needs to
become technologically independent. It
is completely technologically dependent
right now on other nations.
India needs to once again revive the the
space
ISRO
the Indian space program and India needs
to desperately reform the education
system. Yeah,
Prtar Dhana says the Nav'i modest
ambition and Israel situation seems to
be done on purpose. Very suspicious. You
can see yearly launches have decreased
significantly. Absolutely. Let's let's
see
number of space launches by India
per year from 2010 onwards.
Let's see what the Google uh AI says.
2010 10 five launches. 2011 5 2012 23 5
2014 5 2015 5 2016 7 2018 5 20 2017 5
8 2019 6 2022
21 22 4 23 7 launches 24 7 plus launches
this uh 25 as of March 26 only six six
plus launches so very modest modest just
very unambitious
you know that's what India's space
program is is it done on purpose well
obviously it's controlled by the
government of India and if they are not
not taking the space race the the space
program forward it's obviously that they
it means they have chosen not to do that
I don't know why it's the case India can
be a genuine leader in the space race
India has all the potential for that but
uh the government of India doesn't fund
ISRO enough like I've been saying for
does.
Yeah. So, I don't know. It's doesn't
make any sense to me. I have no
explanation for this why the government
of India doesn't consider space to be an
important domain for the country. Very
strange. Very strange.
Sam the Gamer says, "Why do South Africa
always choke?" Cursed? Like how? You
mean in cricket?
See, South Africa don't choke in rugby.
They don't choke in other other sports
but they somehow
can't get past certain hurdles in
cricket.
Uh
yeah. Have they ever reached the final?
They've reached the final right to last
year I think 26 2025 they reached the
final of the T20 World Cup and they they
were about to win that but they lost to
India and there have been many other
occasions where they've choked.
Yeah. In ICC events. So I don't know
maybe it's a mental limitation mental
block. India also had a mental block
against Pakistan. India was to used to
always lose to Pakistan. 1986 onwards
1986 in Shar India was winning a match.
Pakistan needed four runs to win of the
last ball and the Indian bowler bowled a
full toss to Jawad and Dadu for a six
and since then India's psyche broke in
India would always lose to Pakistan
always lose to Pakistan but somehow in
the world cup we started beating them
and we have this tremendous record of
beating them and the past decade or so
we always beat Pakistan so it's been
reversed so it's a psychological block
that you have whether it's South Africa
whether it's India whether it's Pakistan
right now Pakistan also have a
psychological block when it comes to
India. They always lose to India. They
choke when they see India. They simply
don't know how to beat India. So it's a
psychological matter.
A Tal USA says, "What investments should
India make in air defense batteries?"
Um
we have the uh Akash system, right? It's
a tremendously
well battle tested system.
So, we need to get more of those. Maybe
extend the range of the Akash missiles.
Maybe we should get more S400s.
Uh, we we're doing that. We're buying I
think five more batteries of five more
regiments of the S400 system.
And uh so S400 we can augment Akash. We
need to have more of those and maybe
longer ranges. I don't know what the
current range of the Akash system is. Um
let's find out.
Akash missiles range.
Why in Hindi? Good god.
Missile. Missile range.
What's the range? Okay. 4.5 km or 25 30
km. Well, it would be fantastic if you
could make it 100 or 150 km, right? So,
you can always improve a system that you
have. That works fine.
So, we can do that. We need to have
large quantities of these deployed of
the northern northern border with Tibet
and the western border with Pakistan
even the eastern border right. Um we
should have our own S400 kind of system
indigenously designed and built and we
need to have ballistic missile defense
and all those things. So yeah, all that
ICMBB says our first step is to get off
our own delusional horses when there are
people who think ours can beat the F-35s
and to recognize our own shortcomings.
Our what we need to do is to be
realistic,
be completely totally 100% realistic.
We have strengths, we have weaknesses.
The Theis is not the kind of aircraft
that is supposed to go up against
something like the F-35.
The Thus is a short range fighter
interceptor.
It plays a very specific role and it is
pretty good for that role.
You can't compare the Thus with let's
say the Sukoy 30. The Sukoy 30 is a
totally different aircraft for a totally
different role.
So I don't think that it's the right
thing to compare the theas of the F-35.
Theas is a pretty decent fighter plane
and it needs to be improved.
iteratively,
right?
We also have My point is don't be
hyperbolic
and don't be all doom and gloom either.
Be grounded, be balanced, be realistic.
Understand what your limitations are.
Don't go and advertise the limitations
of the world. Keep quiet about them and
work on them.
So I I understand why you are saying
this. There are all these Indians who
say that we are superpower sar, we are
vishuru sar. Those people obviously are
deluded. We are neither superpower nor
vishwaguru
but uh we could be optimistic. We know
that we have great talent and all and we
need to work on our shortcomings.
Harik Jooshi says, "Have you checked
out?" No, no, I have not checked out
Professor Jang.
Um
so he runs a channel called predictive
history geopolitics expert.
He made three huge predictions out of
which two are already true. The third is
coming true. World order changes
according to him.
I have seen one or two of his shorter
videos like five six minute videos
10-minute videos. I simply don't have
the time to watch his longer videos
which are like more than 1 hour long. He
seems to be uh competent. He seems to
know what he's talking about. He clearly
is an expert in whatever he's talking
whatever he's discussing and maybe he's
great. So I have I am not going to watch
his longer videos. I don't have the
time. I I don't watch long podcasts of
videos.
I'm pretty sure is very competent, very
good
and let's not start certainly hero
worshiing individuals also. I would say
I'll be I'll caution people. See the
thing I'm I'm noticing is that YouTube
is pro promoting Professor Jang a
Chinese expert
the Chinese expert Professor Jang has
made the prediction that the US will
lose this war to Iran.
The question is why is an American
platform YouTube promoting a Chinese
expert who says America will lose the
war? Something is fishy here.
So I'll just say be careful about
believing everything you hear and please
don't hero worship any individuals.
Right.
Aris is manticor says just to be clear
the Indian government is explicitly not
going to use chat GPT in any sensitive
departments but they have allowed very
limited usage in less important
departments. I don't agree with this
either for miscellaneous things.
See, Google is setting up a $15 billion
uh facility in I think Vishaka Patnam AI
and from what I hear Indian bureaucrats
will be using Chad GPD
and there's going to be automatic scam
detection etc. Let's let's find out
right
Google Vishaka
AI
AI.
Okay. So, Vishaka Patnam AI
um Google is establishing a massive AI
hub in Mishakapatnam
$15 billion
1 gawatt data centers a campus in
partnership with whatever
it will create a lot of jobs
compute facility.
Okay. What about Google and Google
AI
India bureaucracy?
Uh scam
scam detection.
What was that?
Okay.
So, Google has launched an AI powered
onde device scam detection in India to
com combat whatever.
Um,
where was that news about Indian
bureaucracy? Indian bureaucrats.
Yeah, here we have it. Look at this.
Google is partnering with the Indian
government to train 20 million civil
servants. 20 million civil servants in
AI as part of a civil service reskilling
pledge to transform public
administration.
If Google is going to train 20 million
civil servants, they will do it. Okay,
let's not say charge JPD, they'll do it
on Gemini, which is another American AI,
right?
This collaboration between India and
Google emphasizes AI applications and
public services
uh such as agriculture and potentially
in the judiciary and administrative
sectors.
Judici potentially judiciary and
administrative sectors.
Okay. So this is extremely concerning.
Okay. It's not chart JP. It's Google's
AI. Google's AI is called Gemini, right?
I think so. It's the same thing. Very
very very very very concerning.
Okay. Chiritti says in 6 months Russia
UK Ukraine map could change. It could it
could. It's possible. Yes.
Team talks says before US acted like an
empire but now it's acting and being
vocal about it. What changed? They are
isolating n themselves from every nation
and every nation is seeking
alternatives. It's searching for
alternatives.
Um times have changed. The Americans
have realized, they've allowed China to
rise too high.
And they are realizing the Americans
that the so-called rules-based world
order they created was actually being
more beneficial for their adversaries
and for nations that sought to rise like
India.
So the Americans thus far had until from
1945 all the way till 2022 had been very
quiet about being a superpower, about
being an empire.
But uh now they've decided to
reconfigure the world and that's why
they have got Trump in power right man
for the right time and his job is to
completely reshake the world order
reshake reshape the world order and
that's why the Americans are now
behaving totally differently and this is
going to continue this is the new
America this is the new normal they are
now not just going to be an empire
they're going to act like a empire and
Donald Trump see
Donald Trump's minions like Pete Hexath
and whoever else they're going to be
they're going to acquire the personality
of Donald Trump
in any in any team sport
the team acquires the personality of the
captain you will see that in cricket
very often so
Trump is this very brash arrogant that
sort of guy right outspoken guy so his
minions are going to act just like him
whether it is Pete Hexath whether it is
Scott Lutnik or
Lutnik, Howard Lutnik, whoever else.
Yeah.
Bipol Singh says, "Are we sure or is
there a chance that India has robust
missile and drone stockpiles?"
There's a chance India has robust cruise
missile stockpiles.
There's a chance India has a decent
drone stockpile. I don't think India has
100,000 plus drones. I hope so. I hope
I'm completely wrong but I don't think
so. How many Brahos missiles does India
have? Let's see what Google thinks.
How many Brahmos missiles does India
have?
Official number is classified.
So reports suggest between 1200 to 1500
active missiles. That is peanuts.
In March 25, India approved the
acquisition of 250 250 huge number of
new longer range bramos missiles.
The new production facility in Lucknau
is designed to produce 80 to 100
missiles annually. That is again
peanuts. That's why I'm skeptical about
India having a big stockpile.
What's the point of producing 100
missiles annually?
Let's see
how many shahed drones does Iran produce
per month.
Let's see.
Iran produces 10,000 shahed drones per
month.
Good god. That's the kind of scale India
needs to look into.
How many missiles does India produce?
Iran about a 100 missiles per month but
we talking about ballistic missiles.
Okay. So my point is India is very very
unambitious and very very lagardly in
this in this matters and this needs to
change this needs to change. Yeah.
Jagjit Mida says Shimla agreement terms
pros and cons for India. I don't
remember now. It's it's obsolete. We
walked out of it so it doesn't matter
anymore.
And I don't know why we needed to have
the Shimla agreement with a defeated
nation. So I don't remember the terms of
the Shimla agreement anymore. I what I
remember is that it was never enforced.
It was the Pakistanis never really um
abided by it.
Putin says they just uses Israeli and US
components at Drabata. Indeed. Well even
American aircraft use British components
and other components. So it's impossible
to have complete atmand draba today. But
you should strive to be as atmanderbar
as possible. Um
even Chinese aircraft
use foreign components.
So yeah, you should strive to be atar
and I'm sure there's a long way to go
for India. So we need to work on that.
Uh sasu case says if overall game is to
contain China then why is China not
acting anything? Also why is Russia
silent too impact on India over long
run? I mean, how many questions?
What would you like China and Russia to
do? Anything to do?
Why is Russia silent? Should they
verbally fight the Americans? No, keep
quiet. The oral game is to contain
China. Agree. Why is China not doing
anything? China is going to wait and
wait out this war and see the impact of
this. See how it goes. See, right now,
Iran is doing pretty well.
China is not panicking. Russia is not
panicking. Iran is vital for both
nations.
Both China and Russia are quietly
observing, which means that Iran is
doing pretty well in this war thus far.
If Iran starts doing poorly, Russia and
China may get involved in this matter.
The game is to acquire Iran's oil
resources. That's the American game so
that they can deny it to China.
So if that comes close to happening the
Russians and Chinese may get involved.
Right now Iran is doing well. That's why
the Russians and Chinese are quiet and
they are also quietly helping Iran
indirectly. Impacts on India over the
long run.
Um
we'll have to see
the region has become unstable. The
world is changing now. Uh oil becomes
more precious. Oil becomes more scarce.
India the impact one of the impacts on
India on the long run is that India will
have to depend more on Russian oil which
is a good thing and that will bring
India under American pressure because
America wants India to behave the way
they want us to do. Um impacts will we
will see only once this war is decided.
If Iran loses the war then all the
American focus and pressure will come on
India to fully vitalize India. If Iran
does not win the war, America will have
way less leverage on India.
And if Iran does not lose the war,
uh then
well,
India will have less of a chance of
getting vasalized.
So, a lot of factors in play here. So,
the impact on India will be determined
by the outcome of this war. If the
Americans win, it's it's advantage the
US and hugely disadvantageous to India.
But if America is unable to defeat Iran,
if Iran survives, then it's beneficial
to India.
Louish thin says, "Do you think our
world is controlled by Gus?" What's a
GU?
What's a GU?
I have no idea what a GU is.
What is a gu
full form?
I have no idea what GU means, sir. It'll
be good if you can put the whole thing
so I I understand.
Uh as says, should India make a drone
like Shahed? Yes, India should. India
has this shishnag drone which is similar
to shahed and uh maybe we are inducting
that in some numbers let's see
shishnag drone
shag
sir this is what
Indian version of kamikaz
are we inducting this into the armed
force forces are we
quiet intrigue to longrange drone
warfare
uh shnak drone on 50,000 km and so on so
it looks like we are doing something
about it which is good this is what it
looks like which obviously is quite
similar to the shahed drone so yes we
have this drone I mean somebody has
developed it and we need to induct such
drones the into the military in large
numbers because this is the new way of
doing warfare
Teen Talk says, "You said Trump walked
into a trap, but doesn't it mean that
the deep state is not as smart as we
think? Is it possible that there are
some anti-Americans in it?" Um,
I don't think that the deep state, See,
I don't know who the deep state is, so I
can't say if there are anti-Americans in
it. Um, Trump walked into a trap, but
does it mean the deep state is not as
smart? Maybe the deep state is not as
smart as we think.
Or maybe Trump acted impulsively without
insulting the deep state.
Multiple possibilities.
Maybe the deep state is Israel and maybe
the deep state and maybe Israel wanted
this war no matter what. That's also a
possibility. Who knows? Who knows? It's
very clear look after Marco Rubio's
statements that Israel forced dragged
the US into this war.
So
it's clear from Marco Rubio's statement
that the US
got dragged into the war by Israel by
Netanyahu,
right?
So does it mean that the deep state is
Israel itself or it's Israelis? What is
it? I see without knowing what the deep
state is, we can't really
really answer this question.
Ankit Mishra says Modi visited Israel
right before the attack. Looks like we
have unofficially chosen a side. I said
on day one we have chosen a side. Day
one.
I said this last Saturday we have chosen
a side.
Okay. Given where we are headed, do you
foresee India making a tough call in
relations with Russia four to five years
from now? I
What do I think? What do I what do I
foresee? So, Mr. Modi did visit Israel
right before the attack and then day
after his uh visit there was the attack
on Iran
and we clearly chose a side at least
verbally
right Mr. Modi did not give any
condolences or even state
or even acknowledge the assassination of
of
the supreme leader Kabay
and Mr. Modi through his tweets
condemned the violation of territorial
sovereignty of the Gulf nations.
Obviously without naming it Iran but
Iran.
Um so verbally at least India chose a
side. Now we're not materially choosing
a side. We are not giving America
American warships access to our ports
and we are not participating in the war.
So unofficially I mean verbally we chose
aside but after that we kind of
recalibrated
the Indian foreign secretary went to the
embassy of of Iran and signed the book
expressing condolences on behalf of the
government of India over the
assassination of Mr. Kami. So we are
kind of rebalancing now we are also
giving shelter to an Iranian warship in
in Kochi which again will not please the
Americans. They would like to destroy
all Iranian warships but we are
safeguarding it. Right. So we have
verbally chosen a side but through our
actions we are still
you could say neutral
but overall I have said that there's a
high chance that India will become
vasalized by the United States uh over
the next 5 years there's a high chance
not not 100% certain but high chance so
if we get vasalized by the Americans
over the over the next 5 years we will
make that tough call or Russia and
distance ourselves from ourselves from
Russia in that case I hope that case
doesn't happen of course
Rickin Jane says what's your reason for
retesting
retesting Arvind on excess scops I've
been following him though his theories
are farfetched but all of his tweets
seem pro- India and the national or in
the national interest so even those
tweets of his in which he advocates that
we should purchase Iranian you should we
should purchase uh oil from the
Americans do you think even that is in
the national interest.
See, we have to be very careful about
these matters. We have to be really,
really careful. Give me a second or two.
Let me look into this. Can I find this
guy's tweets?
Um, give me a second. Okay, I'm I'm
digging into it.
I'm sure I'll be able to find something.
Um,
is my browser working? Looks my my
browser is frozen.
Okay. My point is, my point is I have
seen the guy making tweets
that are subtly pro- US that say that we
should purchase
American oil
and that sort of thing which clearly is
not in the national interest.
Am I able to find it?
Probably not. Okay. Okay.
So yeah my point is I have been
observing this account now I don't
remember exactly all the data points
that came into my mind that I observed
my point is be careful okay
DRMPC says not vad it was Avara Musafir
podcast okay
one second
okay
So DM KPC DRMPC
says it was not Vad it was Aar Musafir
podcast
could not could you tell us what's your
proof for the claim of threatening by us
about what I don't remember what your I
don't remember what your original
question was from 1 hour ago
okay so you are asking half the question
earlier half now you you are assuming
that I'll be able to remember what you
asked me I've taken like 50 questions
off of I don't remember what your
question was.
Something you said b and it was not bad.
But what was the question? I can't
recall.
I can't recall.
Could you tell us what's your proof for
the claim of threatening by us? About
what? About what?
About AI.
Sorry, no context.
Suraj Singh says CM change in Bihar.
What's happening internally? I have zero
understanding of Indian politics and
even if I have an understanding I don't
discuss it
manticor says is this war weakening
direct US presence in the Middle East
with so much destroyed the US must be
facing billions in loss they may be
facing a bit of what the EU felt during
the Russia Ukraine war still the US
controls will control Middle East always
so is this war threatening direct US
presence in the Middle East what is the
US presence in the Middle East based on
it's based on the American military
bases in the Middle East. Okay. Now, if
Iran destroys those, the US can't have a
presence there.
Where will you keep the the the
warships, the helicopters, the aircraft,
the the thousands of armed personnel?
Where will you keep them?
You will need radars for safe for for
defending these air bases. What if the
radars are destroyed? So most likely the
the Iranians have severely degraded or
possibly completely destroyed most of
the American military infrastructure and
bases in the Middle East.
Okay,
that's not billions in loss. That's
trillions, trillions in loss.
So that is going to put the American
presence in the Middle East on very
shaky ground.
the Americans won't be able to have a
continuing long-term presence there if
the bases are gone.
Yeah.
So, yes, they are facing a bit of what
the EU faced during failed felt during
the Russia Ukraine war, you know,
depletion of resources
and much more.
Uh, still the US will control Middle
East always. We'll we'll see. We'll see
about that. Hm.
Um, regular everyday MF says, "True
reason for this war? Economic reset,
aliens, AI push. Thanks. The true reason
for this war is to take control of
Iran's oil resources so that you can
deny China the Iranian oil on demand if
required. So let's say tomorrow morning
China decides to admit Taiwan.
If the US controls Iran's oil, it can
stop
everything that's being exported to
China. So suddenly China faces an energy
shortage because 15 to 20% of Chinese
oil comes from Iran. In the America,
Americans already control other
countries like Saudi Arabia, uh the UAE,
Kuwait, Nigeria,
Indonesia and so on so forth. The
Americans can force all these nations to
stop sending selling oil to China. Then
China is in a tremendous crisis. That's
the reason
Anul Jen says Anu Jen says can India be
considered a superpower in diplomacy?
No. You are a superpower in diplomacy
only if you are a genuine superpower.
Okay. So India is not to be considered a
superpower anywhere please.
Shivam says I are the Iranian ship Lavan
is in Kochi. What does that tell us? If
there had been even one US ship in India
many would have called India Vasal of
the US. Yes. Correct. If there was even
one American ship in India, it would
mean that India has taken a very big
decision and that's why it would be
right to perhaps start wondering whether
India has now become a vasal of the US.
But the Iranian ship Lavan is in Kochi.
What does it tell us? Does it perhaps
tell us that India is a vasal of Iran?
No. It tells us that India is sending a
message to the US that we will act
independently of you. You don't get to
tell us what we can do and what we can't
do. We have an independent relationship
with Iran which is independent of our
relationship with the US
and if an Iranian ships needs ship needs
our help then we will give it their
help. So it's what it tells us is that
India is sending a strong message to the
US not through words but through
actions. Okay
Santo, thank you very much sir. Thank
you very much indeed.
The Priyat says
I hope you I hope comes true
in a good way. Mantor says India giving
giving the Lavan refuge could be a
silent message. Exactly like I said this
is a message to the US. It's a message
to the US without words but through
actions. See actions matter. Words don't
matter.
In in this case India is not saying a
single word but it's taking action and
that action sends a message to the US.
Right.
Tanmme Desh Pande says in the Iris Dina
incident is it the Sri Lankan government
who got bullied if anyone was bullied
because they waited 18 11 hours for
permit also we let Iris Lavan dock it's
possible the Americans would have may
have arm twisted the Sri Lankans may
have bullied the Sri Lankans and
prevented the Sri Lankans from giving uh
permission to the uh to the Dana to the
Irish Dana to dock in Gal
It's very it's very possible. I'm not
saying it's likely. It's it's possible
because the Iranians requested Sri Lanka
to give them access to the port and the
Sri Lankans did not say yes or no for 11
hours. And that's those 11 hours is what
the American submarine needed to make
its way all the way to this part of Sri
Lanka, south of Sri Lanka and and
torpedo the ship. So it gave the
Americans time to destroy the Iranian
ship.
So is it a coincidence or were the Sri
Lankans bullied by the Americans into
doing this? I think it's possible the
Sri Lankans may have been bullied by the
Americans and the US is just too
powerful right Sri Lanka what is it
compared to the US. So if the Americans
insist, the Sri Lankans have to agree. I
suppose
Groove Street Hobie says if the US wins,
do they attack India next or other ways?
If the US is able to
achieve its objectives in Iran, which
are Israel's objectives, which is regime
change now. So if the US wins, what
happens? They will train their full
force on India next, not militarily.
not militarily, diplomatically,
economically and so on. They will
essentially force India to become an
American massal
and they will seek to perhaps balconize
India. Uh so it's it won't be a military
offensive on India. It won't be a
military attack on India at all. There
are other ways of defeating a nation.
The Americans tried everything against
Iran, right? They tried uh diplomatic
isolation. They tried sanctions. They
tried everything and when nothing worked
they've taken the military option. So in
case the case of India they will take
all the other options and most likely it
will work if they are able to defeat
Iran. Hopefully not but yeah Santokiran
says Apac's goals of Middle East
dominance and Epstein accused aligning
them together giving fuel to this war.
Your thoughts?
Apac is American politics. What is
Apac's full form? Let me quickly take a
look. America Israel something
AIPAC
American Israel public affairs committee
powerful bipartisan US lobbying group
founded in 1954
that advocates for strong USIsrael
relations and it is a bipartisan group
which means both parties are involved
Republicans and Democrats.
uh AIPAC's goals of Middle Eastern
dominance. Those are Israel's goals of
Middle Eastern dominance. Israel
allegedly has this objective of creating
a greater Israel. That's what some
people allege. I don't know how true it
is or not. But Israel seeks to be the
most dominant nation in the Middle East
and yeah, the whole region overall,
right? So that's Israel's goals.
Epstein accuses aligning together.
Well,
many people have been accused of
being involved with Epstein and those
accusations are based on the
revelations, the Epstein files, and
Donald Trump figures prominently in
that. Donald Trump figures in the
Epstein files in the most disgusting way
possible.
Yeah. Uh and maybe that gives certain
people leverage over Donald Trump
because maybe there's more to be
released.
Uh, and maybe that's why the US got
forced into the war by Israel. It's
possible. I think it's all possible, but
we don't have any proof.
Uh, Omnax says cause Iran's toughness
affect Barat's sovereignty. Well, if
that if that cause produces that effect,
then I am all for it. But Bat should
learn the lesson the lessons of this war
and toughen itself up, right?
Liies says, "Woried Israel,
worried Israel will ditch US and make
India its new host and our sovereignty
will be lost. At least Modi did not go
to the wailing wall.
I I
so the implication is that the US is is
an Israeli vas.
Maybe maybe maybe Israel is the most
powerful nation in the world from that
perspective. Now the question is why
would the Israelis ditch the US in case
they are the Americans have their vasal?
When you have the world's most powerful
empire that's your vasal hypothetically
why would you ditch that and go to
India.
So it's not either or it's and
so in case Israel is that sort of nation
hypothetically that it has vasalized the
US then it may seek to vaselize India
also not replace the US with India it'll
say why not both
hypothetically
okay
says quality has a quantity of its own
that's
quality has a quantity of its own
Russian weapons case. Apparently we can
make Indianized upgraded Suko30s and
send it to Armenia. Why not do it for
ourselves?
Um yeah it it seems that India is close
to selling
a certain number of Sukoy30s to Armenia.
Now we know that India has a shortfall
of fighter planes.
We need at least like I don't know 300
more fighter planes.
So why not build 300 sukois for
ourselves? That's the question.
I think the answer is a little
complicated.
How so? How so? We require certain
numbers of certain types of aircraft.
The Sukoy 30 MKI is a super heavy
fighter plane. It's like massive. It's
like it it dwarfs the huge heavy fighter
plane and it's used typically for long
range penetration missions not for
interceptions
for interceptions
you need a lighter aircraft fighter
interceptor a RAL Rafal is a multi-roll
aircraft which can do interception which
can also do longrange missions so I
think the rules and the requirements are
such that we can't fulfo
for
But you know what? Beggars can't be
choosers. If we don't have the certain
kinds of aircraft and we need a certain
number of aircraft, why not build 300
SEO? So even I'm not sure why we are not
doing that. At least build a 100 more
100 more brand new SEO with more more
enhancements, India specific
enhancements. I don't know.
I don't know.
Prataradana says, "I never thought Iran
would destroy so many US bases." Well,
everyone's been caught unawares.
Everyone's this war has shocked the
world.
I mean, if the you don't you may some of
you may recall in 1991, you may not have
been alive then, but you may have seen
the footage in 1991 when the Americans
launched the first war on Iraq's Iraq.
They broadcast it live. Live telecast of
the American bombing, carpet bombing of
Ther Baghdad and whatnot. CNN used to
show it live night vision and and the
the Iraqi tracer rounds and shells
trying to hit the American aircraft, but
they they are carpet bombing the city
with impunity. So the Americans were
live streaming, live broadcasting
everything. How come they are not live?
And the Americans are all about American
glory and all right that we can destroy
everybody and let's show it showcase it
to the world. So if that's the case, why
are they not live streaming and live
broadcasting what they're doing in Iran
right now? Because things are not going
their way.
So yeah, it's it's
one must say well played Iran thus far.
Yeah, they have shocked the world.
They've shocked the Americans.
Looks like they have essentially
you know
caused significant destruction to or if
if if not completely destroyed the
American bases in the region. Yeah. So
lessons that India needs to learn from
this. I'm not saying India should fight
the US. I'm just saying India should
learn the lessons for any future war
with anybody.
Anu Jan says, "What can be the reason of
India government not privatizing
Hindustan?"
Hul what is Hul?
Hindustan Util Utilities Limited.
Hindustan Aeronautics Limited. I have no
idea. I don't know. No idea.
Priyat says, "I build AI servers in the
US. We use Nvidia's Blackwell GPUs.
Where does India's GPU game where does
India's GPU come from to build GPU node
AI servers? Are we using Nvidia or AMD
GPUs? That's not tech sovereign. I don't
know where it comes from, but it's
definitely not Indian GPUs. Probably
Nvidia, I suppose. Yeah, I think it's
probably Nvidia.
Um, India is not technologically
sovereign.
India is the techno see if you have
see each element of sovereignty we can
give it a score between one and zero
like economic sovereignty territorial
sovereignty so on so forth so in
technological sovereignty India would
have a score close to 0.1 or 0.2 at most
where 1.0 is full sovereignty
the US is close to 1.0 0 some of its
technology comes from other countries
but it is countries that the US controls
so that's why I would say the US has a
technological sovereignty score of 1.0
zero China would be around8
maybe even 85
China also depends on for example it
depends on uh ASML's photoiththography
machines for semiconductor manufacturing
and all that for for chip manufacturing
so China is despite that I would say
China would have a technological
sovereignty score of 0.85
Russia would be close to 0.8 or
something India is 0.1 or 0.2 into at
most India is not technologically
sovereign. So India's GPUs come from the
US or from Taiwan.
Okay. Now India is taking its own steps
in setting up semiconductor
manufacturing which eventually at some
point in time will have will produce
indigenous Indian GPUs but right now we
are far from doing that. Yeah.
So I don't know which specific GPUs
India is using but they are definitely
Nvidia or whatever per perhaps AMD not
India.
Aayush Goyel says don't know if you have
covered this before but why does the US
support Israel so much is it just
lobbying or its US plan to control the
Middle East?
Well,
Israel has a lot of influence in the US.
They have AIP, AIPC, which is a
bipartisan lobbying group in which you
have you have members of political
politicians from both parties in the US.
Uh you have Jewish American politicians
who are extremely influential, extremely
powerful on both sides of the of the
aisle. Right? So that's why that's one
of the reason why the US supports Israel
so much because so many of the most
powerful politicians are Jewish
and the Jewish people their homeland
religious ethnic spiritual homeland is
obviously Israel. So these are perhaps
the reasons why the US supports Israel
so much. It's not about controlling the
Middle East, it's about supporting
Israel. And of course if you uh have an
ally in Israel then you can certainly
control the Middle East because Israel
is the most powerful nation in the
region. Well was thought to be the most
powerful nation in the region. It still
is considering its nuclear capabilities.
Goullibar says we need to keep an eye on
Nepal. Balen is said to be become PM.
He's either extremely nationalistic for
Nepal or US ally. He's backed by if he's
backed by the US then we have US third
proxy Pakistan Bangladesh Nepal Balencia
is most likely a US asset
okay
and he could become the PM right he he's
a what vlogger blogger something
something like that
and suddenly he's like the top
politician he is a US asset okay
uh so if he becomes PM which seems
likely Then we will have three proxies,
American proxies in our backyard.
Like I said, it's a strategy of
containment and encirclement by the US.
Tjis Shilgamar says, why do Americans
openly tweet about influencing India if
Vasal control works best unseen? Won't
that alert us Indians more to put
pressure on our government?
When you are so confident that you are
going to succeed no matter what happens,
you'll tweet about it openly.
It's hubris. It's arrogance.
When you believe that your target has no
choice, there is no chance. And when
you're just convinced that you have
overwhelming superiority,
then you will display this arrogance on
Twitter.
Yeah. I mean you can see the the way the
Americans communicate and tweet about
India
and whether it's done openly or not most
Indians even if it's done openly will
not understand what's happening because
most Indians aren't on Twitter first of
all right so when the Americans tweet
about this especially American decision
makers policy makers politicians
officials it's they're not tweeting to
us they're tweeting to their own to
their
public
it's political messaging for back home
and most Indians aren't on aren't on
Twitter and those Indians who are on
Twitter also won't understand this see
Indians don't think critically so that's
why it gives other nations an advantage
abe says foreign minister Indian ocean
isn't just regional
a major shift I have no idea what the
foreign minister said let's find out
jaw shankar Indian ocean isn't just
regional
What's that?
India's rise will be determined by its
own strength. Statements are statements
and fine.
Um,
what is this?
Indian Ocean isn't a regional only club.
Okay, let's see. Let's see this. That's
the statement I think you're referring
to.
So what is the statement?
Oh god, no. Let's mute that. Okay, it's
muted. Can I pause this please? Yeah,
thank you. Foreign Minister Jashankar
said that the Indian Ocean isn't a
regional only club. The US base on Diego
Garcia for 50 plus years proves extra
regional powers belong in the Indian
Ocean. It's a global arena not a private
pond.
And this diag person says this is a
brutal slam of the social media
warriors. No, it is an acknowledgement
for the first time of India's weakness.
So when Junkr says this, what does it
mean? It means that it is not India's
backyard.
It is not only for regional players like
India. Even the Americans have a
presence here and they they have it for
50 years. So those of you who are
claiming that it's a that that it's
India strategic backyard, you are wrong.
So it is a U-turn by India.
India had this famous slogan
until like last week I think that the
Indian Ocean is our strategic backyard.
Now the foreign minister is saying it's
not our strategic backyard.
It's a global club. It's a global
players place. So India is kind of
seeding space in the Indian Ocean. And
India is now saying that we are not
powerful enough to dominate the Indian
Ocean. We will only do coastal defense
essentially
not exactly that maybe be more than that
but it's an acknowledgement that the
Indian Ocean is not our
exclusive strategic backyard
the US is more powerful than India in
the in our own neighborhood it means
right yeah
Ankita Kachab says good evening ma'am do
you see anyone emerging as a winner of
this ongoing war supposing that nukes
won't be used
so Good question. Uh
winner. So the word winner depends on
victory
and victory we have to understand that
everybody has a different definition of
victory. For the US victory will mean a
regime change in Iran.
I mean Trump has been flip-flopping
flip-flopping on this matter. On day one
Trump said that they seek regime change
and he called upon the people of Iran to
be ready to take over the government.
Then 3 days later he says no the goal
posts have shifted and we only see seek
the demilitarization of Iran and the
denuclearization of Iran. So goal posts
changed. Now Trump says that he is
funding and supporting Kuresh militias
to fight Iran which once again means
regime change is back on the cards.
So for the US victory will mean regime
change in Thran. For Israel victory will
mean regime change in Thran. For Iran,
victory will mean survival.
So if Iran is still
surviving
by the time the war ends, Iran will say
we have won.
And if if Iran survives though till the
end of the war even if the US has not
been defeated militarily as such they
have lost the military campaign. they've
failed to achieve their objectives and
so for same for Israel. So what do I see
happening?
I would put my money if I was a betting
person which I'm not but if I was a
betting person I would put my money on
Iran surviving.
Even if nukes are used, Iran will
survive.
Even if the Israelis or Americans nuke
Iran, let's say they drop 10 nukes on
Iran, Iran will still fight. They will
not stop fighting the way the Japanese
surrendered. Iran won't stop fighting.
They'll fight in the fields. They'll
fight on fight in the streets. They'll
fight on the beaches. They'll fight
everywhere.
Kind of like what Winston Churchill
said, that sort of thing.
So, if I was a betting person, which I'm
not, but if I was, my money would be on
Iran. I see Iran emerging as the as a as
the survivor and winner, which doesn't
mean it's a military defeat for the US,
but it's a failure of the military
campaign in Israel. We don't know.
Israel could end up being taking immense
immense
damage.
Chaitan says why after 1,000 years of
foreign invasions, occupation,
colonization, Indians are so ignorant
about foreign threats even today. How
many years still required to learn? Why
are Indians ignorant about these
matters? Because our education system
doesn't teach us these matters. As
simple as that. You spend how many years
in school and college. You start at the
age of let's say five or four. Let's say
four
and you go on until the age the age of
22 or something. If you finish college,
no. If you finish college,
let's say it's 15 17 years in in
education.
Shouldn't you be taught about these
matters?
Shouldn't you be taught what the
national interest is? Shouldn't you be
taught your real history? Shouldn't you
be taught the lessons that we should
learn from our history? We are taught
none of these things. We're taught lies.
So what is So why are Indians like this
so ignorant? I don't blame our people
for this. It's not their fault.
It's not their fault. Let's not get
upset with our people. It's the
education system that has made this to
done this to them. That is the simple
answer. Education system.
Putin says, "Is Iran indirectly smacking
American weapon lobby in India?"
Indirect effects can be all kinds of
effects, but Iran is only doing one
thing. It's trying to survive. It's all
Iran is trying to do. It's trying to
survive.
Um,
indirectly smacking American weapons
lobby. Well, American weapons, they're
fine. We're not buying American Patriot
interceptor missiles, right?
Those make no sense for India. I'm sure
their weapons are still good, right?
So, this is not a failure of the US uh
weapons that we are seeing. This is a
failure of America's strategic
foresight.
It's America's strategy that is wrong.
In India, America's warfighting doctrine
that is outdated.
That's the failure.
Rushab man says Gulf Iran funds radicals
in India. Their economic decline will
reduce this funding. Our experts can
find work in EU, Australia, USA for
remance remittance thoughts. Uh there
are various Gulf nations. I will refrain
from taking their names. Who fund
radicalism in India?
Does Iran fund radicalism? I suppose
there could be some funding coming from
Iran into Shia activities into in India.
But are did the Iranians ever fund
terrorism in India or radicalization in
India? I doubt it.
I doubt it.
I haven't seen any evidence of that. I
could be wrong obviously.
Gulf nations we know that
they have fun some of them have funded
radicalization
uh terrorism indirectly etc. in India.
I don't think Iran has ever funded
terrorism anti-India terrorism anywhere.
radicalization. I'm not sure.
Um, so the economic decline of the Gulf
nations will reduce this funding to
India. Yes, I agree.
Or experts can find find work in you
wherever for remittance.
My question is why do we need to depend
on remittances?
It's like living the life of a beggar,
right?
Why do we need Indians to be expatriots?
You can be expats for pleasure. Sure, I
want to travel the world. I'll be an
expat. That's fine. But our experts are
economic migrants. They're economic
refugees. Why can't we make India better
so that nobody has to become an economic
refugee? You can become an expert only
if you feel like traveling and wandering
the world.
So um that's a different story. My point
is Gulf decline
the na the decline of Gulf nations
economic decline could certainly
certainly reduce funding to to
extremists and other radicals in India.
Sure.
VPS good to see you sir. How are you?
I'm I'm good. How are you too? Hope
you're doing great. Jesam to you sir as
well. Thank you.
The posture
says good evening. Uh good evening. Do
you think it's in our interest if
Pakistan get gets involved in a war with
Iran? Iran may possibly vanish military
bases of Pakistan in a week.
Look, if Pakistan gets involved with
Iran, I'll tell you what, Iran is
fighting a multiple front war in India.
We worry about fighting a two-front war
with China and Pakistan and maybe 2.5
war because we have issues within within
India. So, we worry about a two front or
two 2.5 war. Iran is fighting a clear
two-front war at least US and Israel.
But Iran is also targeting other nations
from where the various American military
bases are are based. So Iran is fighting
like essentially a 7 8 n front war right
now.
And if Pakistan gets involved in it,
it's going to be a 10-front war perhaps.
the odds will be stacked up against Iran
in that case because Pakistan whe they
like it or not has a professional
military wellunded military the Pak the
nation of Pakistan is bankrupt but the
military is reasonably well funded
uh so it'll be bad for Iran
but uh who knows Iran may may be able to
vanquish Pakistan too in which case it
is good for us so look if Pakistan takes
damage it's good it's it's good for us
Pakistan is a terrorist nation which
doesn't deserve to exist actually. So if
Pakistan gets dam takes damage, it will
be good for us. So for example, if the
Pakistanis start hosting American
warships in Karachi or Guada, maybe the
Iranians will take out Godar and Karachi
ports. That will be good for us. So
overall, yeah, if our enemy
gets uh involved in a war, it's good for
us.
VSVS says humble request to ban achiever
and ajay they are calling us wasal guru
which is disrespected a critic see I am
answering questions right now I don't
think my moderator is online today so
yeah right now I cannot in real time go
and look for these people what what's
the names
achiever and aay
I can quickly try and see who these
individuals are
I see There are hundreds of messages.
It's physically impossible for me to
look into that and then I'll waste time
and not be able to answer questions. So
maybe I can ban those people later if
they are being nasty. But right now I'm
going to have to keep answering
questions. I can't look at the live chat
and yeah anyway thank you for letting me
know. I'll look into this later. I can I
can even do it later. Don't worry.
Golibar says given the stakes in public
office like MEA I believe ministers
whose immediate family is primarily
separate settle abroad may face
potential vulnerable vulnerabilities to
external pressure even if the risk
doesn't materialize in every case I
completely agree with you the Chinese
have a very clear policy right they they
have categorized officials Chinese
officials whose families are settled
abroad they've categorized them as naked
officials and they have said that you
either bring your family's back or
resign or not resign be thrown out be be
expelled from their post that is a
prudent course of action now in India
every Tom Dick and Harry official
whether it's a bureaucrat or whoever
else
they have children studying abroad they
have uh children with foreign passports
family settled abroad which means that
they believe rightfully that their
entire family's future lies outside the
country then why are you serving this
country then pretending to serve the
country right when you when your family
is settled abroad it means your future
lies there which means your allegiance
most likely lies there so India needs to
look into this very carefully
okay it's a real issue it's a real issue
can the government of India make do
something about is they should yeah
Phoenix music says you say professor
Jang is interesting but at times I think
you are interesting haha okay thank you
thoughts about his theory of pax judika
will Iran go for zorastri zoroastrianism
I am not aware of his theory of pax
judika I haven't watched his videos so I
can't say I was not aware that he had a
theory of pax judika I've seen one or
two of his shorter clips like 8 10
minutes or thing was I don't remember
what what it was about. So clearly he's
an interesting guy. He's competent. He
knows what he's talking about. He's not
clueless like many people are like many
experts are. He is clearly very
competent
and therefore interesting.
Uh but I have I'm not aware of his
theory of Pakaya.
Will Iran go for zoroastrinism?
If Iran does not lose this war, which
means Iran survives, then Iran will not
go for zoroastrinism. will remain as a
Shia Shia nation Shia nation. If Iran
loses the war, which means the Americans
win and achieve a regime change in Iran,
then the Americans will flood Iran with
Christian missionaries, which in which
case India Iran will in the next few
decades become a Christian nation.
So either this way or that way, Iran is
not going for Zuruastianism. That's how
I see it going.
Vikram says Christianity is declining in
the west. Why aren't they trying to fix
it there instead of trying to spread it
in India, Africa, etc. The western world
is now geared towards atheism,
transhumanism, all those things. They
worship technology, they've worshiped
logic, etc. And uh they are moving away
from religion gradually or significantly
though it's already happened, right?
Most people, I would imagine in Western
Europe don't identify as religious. Most
people of the most people are atheists.
The pope is irrelevant today
in Western Europe possibly the I don't
know about the US is American right this
pope the current pope um so the US is
the last large country large first world
western country where Christianity is
still relevant to some extent so why
aren't they trying to fix it because
like I said they are moving towards
atheism and all that and they don't see
Christianity as being too relevant now
they don't see Christianity as being
capable
of being a political religion that can
control the people because now people
know about Christianity. People know the
g the game that was played by the popes
and all that. They they understand now
that Christianity isn't what it has
claimed to be. They understand how
Christianity was used to subjugate and
control the people of Europe for close
to a thousand years. So people in the
west are now aware. They're they're
awake
woke
and that's why they are no longer
interested in Christianity. But
Christianity has to survive somehow. So
go after the the the backward third
world countries.
That's where they will keep it relevant
so that they can still control a major
portion of humanity. That's the that's a
that's the deal.
Surya Mahavir Karna says how to build
insight like yours to impact history.
You build up insights by study through
study. You don't spend years studying
things to to have real insights.
You can get started
in a field in a topic through podcasts.
But a podcast will not make you an
expert in anything. So let's say you
read 50 books as opposed to read 50.
Let's say one person reads 50 books and
let's say one person consumes 500
podcasts.
The person who reads 50 books will be
far ahead of the person who consumes 500
podcasts
because reading is a whole different
mental activity.
So how do you build insights?
You build insights by reading by
studying
diligently.
Okay. So do get your inspiration from
podcasts, from askabit, from other
people as well. But if you want to build
real insights, deep insights, original
insights, you have to study, you have to
read, you also have to write.
After reading, write down your own
thoughts. That's how you build original
insights. That's what you do.
Mi says, "Yes, India's performance. You
can search up JP Morgan PMI index. The
link by JP Morgan AM. It's a graphic.
The general expansion is a good sign.
Let's see. Let's see. Okay.
Um
JP Morgan PMI index.
Let's see. Uh is this is this the one?
Let's see. Let's go in there.
Uh the link by JP Morgan. This is SPG
Global. Not this one.
This one. Okay. Let's see.
Uhhuh.
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Global
purchasing managers index PMI for
manufacturing. Okay. So let's see where
India stands in all this.
So India is essentially all green since
in the 2020s. All green. The Euro zone
is getting red and then yellow. France
is red. Germany is red. recession. Spain
is doing okay. Switzerland is doing
fine, but it's tiny. Good for them. UK
is doing okay, I suppose. No, they're
doing terribly. I'm sorry. Switzerland
is all red. Sweden is green. Greece is
green. Good for them. Good for them.
Spain is doing okay. Switzerland is red.
That's bad. US is doing okayish. Japan
is all n good these days. Indonesia
doesn't Korea doesn't seem to be doing
too well. But look at India.
It's all green, right?
Um, a score of 50 indicates that
economic activity is either expanding
not neither expanding nor contracting.
Above 50 indicates expansion.
Below 50 indicates contraction. So,
India is 55 and 55.4
2026 December to January. So India is
constantly
and consistently expanding.
That's the general expansion is a good
sign. I completely agree with you.
Outstanding. Outstanding. Yeah.
Completely agree with you. Yep.
Okay. Right angle says Indian Navy has
zero MCMVs. Other nations are 40. What's
MCMV? Let's see quickly.
MCMV
mine counter measures vessel. Good god,
we don't have any.
Well, mines typically are super
effective in choke points,
geographic choke points like straight of
foremost, the straight of Babal Mandib,
straight of Malaa etc. Suis
we don't have any major such choke
points in
our region. Malaka of course extended
region we have Malaka Babal band and
hormones
but mines are still a concern and why
don't we have mine clear countermeasures
vessels I have no idea that's terrible
uh Nirmal says I am new here why is
Israel sovereign they are dependent on
the US no dependent on the they are
dependent on the US but I I still
consider them to be sovereign because
the US gives them unconditional support
no matter what happens
When you have the unconditional support
of the superpower, you are not
sovereign, you are super sovereign.
Okay.
Apart from that, they have uh
territorial sovereignty, they have
economic sovereignty, they have military
sovereignty.
Technologically also they're pretty
sovereign. Maybe not 100% but overall
pretty sovereign. And I don't I don't
consider technological sovereignty thus
far into my formula, my equation for
sovereignty. and they have the
unconditional support of the US. I mean
what else do you need? So that's why
they're super sovereign actually.
Uh VSB says achiever DJ7 says you are
funded by Adani
and Bhim Gita domain expansion. I have
no idea what that means. I am not
funded. I wish I wish I wish
I wish I am funded by nobody.
Okay. I'm entirely self-funded.
Vikram say okay Vikram thank you very
much Vikram thank you so much very much
indeed
Animish Bharti has gifted 10 memberships
of this channel to 10 people thank you
so much Anish it's very kind of you very
generous of you I thank you on behalf of
each person who received the membership
thank you
the posture says YouTube acting weird it
doesn't give notification of your live
stream describe despite me subscribing
to your live stream today morning you
should host somewhere else well YouTube
has acting weird for
for quite some time with when it comes
to my channel. I get this all the time.
People don't get notifications even
though they have signed up for
notifications.
Um and so much more. I mean my
subscriber count is has been stuck
between 249 and 251. What's it right
now?
What's it right now? It's two uh 952. So
for a year and a half it was 949.
people were getting automatically
unsubscribed.
I've even heard that people are not able
to comment.
So what can I say? I should host
somewhere else. Well, YouTube is the
place where everybody comes to watch,
right? I can set up my own OTT or
something. But who will come and watch?
The place where everybody gathers.
That's where you should do your thing.
So YouTube is the place where one can do
that. I can host it somewhere else but
nobody will be there. Nobody will come
there.
VSVS has gifted 10 memberships of the
channel. Thank you very much VSVS sir
ma'am. Thank you so much. It's very kind
of you. I thank you on behalf of each
person who has received the memberships.
Thank you. Right angle says P75i project
signed in 2002 but not completed thus
far. My my views my views is that
extremely extremely frustrating and
disappointing. Very disappointing. The
submarine project very disappointing.
Orodash says E 100 EV hydrogen petrol
pressure on government. I have no idea.
I'm not keeping track on this.
Uh electric vehicles hydrogen down
patrol pressure on government. I don't
know. Maybe
Sansky says, "Is our sovereignty
compromised?"
Yes.
If you have
50 million to 100 million Bangladeshes
in your in your territory,
are you really sovereign?
A sovereign nation is a nation that does
not allow or tolerate
criminals, illegal immigrants.
What if you have 50 million illegal
immigrants or 100 million or 30 million
even then your sovereignty is is
question is under huge question.
If you can't keep illegals out, it means
you are not really sovereign.
That's just one data point. sovereignty
compromised.
Look at Manipur. Does the Indian
government control 50% of Manipur?
Big question mark there once again. Once
again, foreigners squatting on Indian
territory,
right?
And there's more like um technologically
we are a non-s sovereign nation.
If the Indian government allows Google
AI to to
to underpin the bureaucracy. Well, once
again, so loss of sovereignty. So,
sovereignty is definitely kind of
compromised right now. We need to work
on this.
Rahul says, "Your thoughts on new union
territory being planned? I've heard
something about something in the
vicinity of Bengal perhaps." Uh, but I'm
not sure about what exactly the deal is.
So, I will refrain from commenting about
that because I'm not sure what it is.
Right angle says, "Did do we
does we outsourced our AI? Do you use
maple map?"
Uh, I don't know what maple map is. So,
I don't use that.
Do we outsource our AI? We should not
outsource AI. We should have our own
sovereign AI AI
AI models. We should have our own
sovereign AI models.
Droop says
war impact on Indian people. I run a AI
agency for clients for foreign clients.
Um I don't think your business will be
impacted. You run an AI agency for
foreign clients,
right? The war is not going to impact
that.
The war is going to impact the Indian
person in the sense that if the state of
hormones remains closed for a longer
time then the prices the price of oil
will shoot up significantly maybe $150
per barrel. If oil is expensive petrol
and everything diesel is expensive which
makes transportation expensive which
means all your goods
vegetables tomatoes potatoes onions they
their price will rise. the price of
everything rises, the price of home
delivery rises, price of restaurant food
rises, the price of all commodities
rise. So that's hardship for the people,
right? So that's the kind of impact it's
going to have on the common person, not
just in India but across the world if
this continues and it seems likely to
continue. Uh apart from that for India
that doesn't seem to be much of any
other kind of effect thus far at least.
Um
and for foreign clients so so your
business in the short to medium term I
don't see much of an impact okay
Vun Bajaj says India buying German
submarines my thoughts
we need to stop buying things and start
manufacturing things I mean it's fine
that we are buying
we want to have a menagerie of different
kinds of things like we have like 17
different fighter aircraft and we should
now have 23 different kinds of
submarines. Is it like that? I mean,
looks like that's what we're trying to
achieve.
We already had a production line for the
scorpion submarines, right? Why did did
we decide to do that? Was there some
issue with the scorpions? There was some
some issue somewhere. Some French uh
military person leaked some data about
the scorpions. Did is that why we did
not continue with more sub scorpions?
Um, now German submarines. I mean
Germany is the US vasal. Let me be very
explicit about that. Is it I mean I I'm
I understand buying French submarines.
French the French are quasi sovereign
but the Germans are outright American
vasiles. 100% vasals.
Why buy German submarines? Are they that
good?
If that's the case, why not buy the
Swedish Gotland class? Those are
brilliant.
So, uh we need to make everything
ourselves. We have to be at in these
matters and that's why it is overall.
Ritik says our MEA is following Aravidon
X. I wonder why. Well, that is
interesting. Let's see.
Um,
do I have something?
Where could I find this?
Okay, let's let's
give me a second. Second.
Okay, let's open a new instance of
Google and let's try and find this out.
Our MEA is following Aravind on X
MEA India Twitter
Twitter.
Let's see how many handles
are being followed.
221.
Let's see.
Good God,
they're following Aravind.
Well, well, well. I
I also wonder why. That's all I can say.
I wonder why. What? Seriously, following
an anonymous account.
Okay.
Struggler says, "What if the US or
Israel attacked the ship in Kochi?" The
Israelis don't have the capability to do
the do that. The Americans have the
capability to do that. But that that is
a declaration of war against India.
Attacking a ship in an Indian port is an
is essentially a declaration of war. I
don't think the US will do that. If the
US does that, India will well India that
it guarantees India will not become an
American masal
because it's politically disastrous for
India to align with the US after the US
does such a thing. So it's not going to
happen in the first place.
VPS says is Lal Bahadur the great
Shastri G underrated as a prime minister
also don't you think
Am Modi is truly Batman as PM Modi
am Modi is truly Batman as PM Modi okay
the joke aside joke I'll take later
underrated as a prime minister well we
won the 1965 war while Mr. Shastri was
prime minister,
right? Um I think so. Lal Badu Shastri
died in which year?
Um
okay, one second. Okay, let's see.
Lal Bahadur Shastri,
he died in 1966.
So yes, he was the prime minister in
1965 when the war happened. I see I
haven't studied his life history in
great detail or something. So I don't
know much about him.
Yeah, we don't really talk about Mr.
Shastri as as prime minister. I I don't
know whether he's underrated. Uh so
cancer. Sorry. Uh don't you think am
Modi is truly Batman as PM Modi? I don't
know what Batman is, but AM Modi PM
Modi. Interesting. Funny.
Um Banani says just check the Chinese
have banned USI. Of course it makes
sense for them to ban USAI. It makes
sense for them to do that. Any
self-respecting sovereign nation will do
that right.
VSB says sir protect your friend Abijit
Oraj from anti-gay hate in my chat. Oh
really? Why is there anti-gay hate?
Let's refrain from doing such things.
Yeah,
we should not
uh discriminate ba based on things like
that sexual uh orientation or whatever.
Good person is a good person
irrespective of whatever they do.
Okay. Swami says consequences of the US
puts boots on the ground in Iran. Iran
loses. No, US loses.
Saddam Hussein tried to put boots on the
ground. He was not far away from Iran.
He was right next door. His
army was able to advance 50 kilometers
and then they got stuck for 100 for for
10 years.
Boots on the ground in Iran is suicidal.
I'll show you why it's suicidal.
Okay, give me a second.
Give me a second. I'll show you why it's
suicidal. Iran is a fortress.
Let's let's go instead of going to the
map of Iran, I'm going to show you a
different kind of map of map of Iran. A
non-interactive
map of Iran. This is Iran.
Iran is mountains, mountains, mountains
everywhere. Okay?
It's protected on all sides by
mountains. It is like Afghanistan plus.
Why do the Afghanistan always
successfully fight successfully fight
foreign invaders? Because Afghanistan is
a mountainous country and the defenders
of Afghanistan can can hide out in the
mountains and keep fighting forever. Now
look at Iran. If the Americans try to
put boots in the ground, it's going to
be suicidal for them. Iran is a
fortress. It can be defended
indefinitely.
Consequences will be disastrous for the
US if they put boots in the ground.
That's why they will go with with with
proxies like the Kurds or whoever.
VS says the world is controlled by only
controlled by Guju Bhim Gita readers
readers. Okay, if he says so. Pantic
Gamer says what's your basis of saying
Iran is doing pretty well especially
after absolutely losing air dominance
politically decapitated SRM is
destroyed. agree in peace with
neighbors.
Okay. Why do I say this? Right. Uh yeah,
they have lost air dominance from what
we hear. From what we hear, uh they have
been politically decapitated.
Their SRMBB short range.
What is SRMBB? Give me a second.
Um
you mean SRBM?
SR MB. What is SRB? steel. I think
you're saying SRBMs, short-range
ballistic missiles destroyed. How do you
know it's destroyed? Who told you? The
American media told you. This is what
happens when you just pay attention to
the media diet that's fed to you. The
Western media.
Why am I saying Iran is doing well?
Because they are still sovereign.
Because they've destroyed or badly
damaged all the American military bases
in the region.
They've imposed a tremendous amount of
punishment and damage on Iran, on Tel
Aviv. They're still launching drones
every day. They're still launching
missiles every day.
The American aircraft carriers have
escaped far away from
the vicinity of Iran. Why have the
aircraft carriers which are the
supposedly the most powerful ships in
the world, why have they been forced to
move far away?
If they are politically decapitated, how
come they are still coordinating
everything in real time, all the strikes
and all that?
They're agreeing to peace with neighbors
after destroying the American military
bases on in on those neighbors territory
and it's still a conditional peace.
So my assessment is based on my
understanding and what I observe of
things. You can definitely feel free to
disagree,
but Iran is going to keep fighting. Iran
is doing pretty well. Let's come back in
a week's time and see where we are. Iran
is going to still fighting. Would you
agree after if if one week from today if
Iran is still fighting and has not been
regime changed, then Iran is doing
pretty well.
I mean on on one side you have the
United States and Israel. One is a
superpower, the other is a regional
power. On the other hand, you have a
nation that's been sanctioned for like
50 years,
economically bankrupted nation cut off
from the rest of the world and they're
still fighting.
So I think Iran is doing pretty well.
Kakashi says is Cuba,
North Korea, Belarus and Nicaragua
sovereign? There are only six sovereign
nations in the world. Only six. The US,
Russia, China,
India,
US, Russia, China, India,
and Iran. Am I missing something?
I am the guy who came up with this. I
should not miss something.
I came up with the sovereignty
framework, right? Give me a second.
Israel of Oh, Israel. Israel. Yeah.
It's
here we have it.
So this framework of mine was now being
plagiarized by everybody. Everybody was
was putting it out as if it's their it's
their invention or their creation. So
this is it. There are six sovereign
nations only six. The US, Russia, China,
India, Israel and Iran. That is it. No
other nation.
So people get upset about that also.
People say why not this? Why not that?
It is what it is. I've explained why.
Pratarana says, "I noticed India is full
of MOS ad YouTubers." What's MOS?
Ministry of State.
Okay.
Uh I don't know because I I have YouTube
premium. I pay a little bit of money
every month for that. Yeah. So that
there are no ads. So I I don't know what
ads are there right now. Interesting.
Okay.
vs says if Trump doies fam revives Bhim
Gita.
Okay, I have no idea what that is but
all right sir. Ankush Sharma photography
says if deep state pro approved
an deal when Obama why click click click
when Trump what
if deep state approved an nuclear deal
when Obama
why cancel canceled when Trump because
Trump decided to walk out of the deal it
was a betrayal of Iran the nuclear deal
Iran agreed to all the conditions that
the Americans were asking were imposing
but demanding. The Iranians agreed to do
everything. The Americans said they even
opened up their nuclear facilities for
inspection by the International Atomic
Energy Agency, IAEA. The Iranians did
everything they were asked to do
as part of the JCPO, a joint
comprehensive plan of action. And then
Trump comes to power and he walks out of
the deal unilaterally. It was a
betrayal. It was a backstabbing.
Yeah.
Kakashi says Venezuela and Syria were
sovereign until recently. No,
there's a difference between being
nominally sovereign and being really
sovereign, geopolitically sovereign.
That way you will say even Japan is
sovereign, right?
Syria was completely dependent on Russia
for its survival.
That's not the hallmark of sovereignty
where your so sovereignty where your
survival depends on a foreign nation.
You're not sovereign. You're completely
dependent.
And Venezuela was sanctioned by the US
and so on, but it was able to survive
because it was exporting oil to China
and some other countries,
but it was very badly constrained by
sanctions and so on.
So, you can't really say it was
sovereign.
VSVS says uh questioned by radical Trump
truthed so shield that Iran lost. But
Trump makes 15 claims every single
morning and then walks back the next day
in 2025
after the end of the 12-day war against
Iran. Trump tweeted and announced to the
world that Iran has Iran's nuclear
program has been permanently destroyed.
He said that that Iran's nuclear program
has been permanently destroyed. Now when
he starts this war in 2026, he said that
we are doing we are we are attacking
Iran because we want to end its nuclear
program. So was he lying in 25 or is he
lying today? Trump is a habitual liar.
Pratu Sharma says another TH has been
destroyed in Jordan right now. All
right. All right. All right.
And then they ask uh how come Iran is
doing well?
Let me try and see if I can find
something about this. Usually I look for
information on X.
Okay. Wow. Got 50 plus questions still
remaining and it's three plus hours.
So let's um give me a second. Give me a
second. All right. Let's go to X and see
if we can find something about Todd.
T H A D.
Uh
let's see.
Do we have any more recent immediate
news?
And Grock will always always take a pro-
US stance. Okay, please remember that.
Okay. So, I'll not try and search for
this in real time because it'll waste
our time. Okay.
Um Okay. Third destruction in Jordan Cub
by random. Okay. Uh yeah, we we'll we'll
keep an an eye on that. We'll keep an
eye on that. Yeah.
Lish says, "Do you think this war has
something something to do with building
of the third temple in Jerusalem?" Also
four five red hers were brought to
Israel from the US in 2022. I am not
familiar with the Jewish uh
religion and uh prophecies and stuff. Um
there seems to be some prophetic thing
about burning of red hyers
and the temple can happen then and
Armageddon. I think the Americans are
also launching a crusade of some kind,
right? I mean their military personnel
are being told that this war is for
Armageddon. We are we want to bring
about the end of the world so that Jesus
Christ can be reb born or something like
that. I I don't know about these
religious matters. I
these are these religions are foreign to
me. So I don't know much about them in
much detail. So it's possible that there
is
that there may that war may have
something to do with that building of
the third temple
but I'm not quite sure what it could be.
Ram Ramaranga thank you very much
Ramaranga G thank you vss thank you very
much sirra
says deep state is masonic military
corporate industrial complex of US joy
chalat
and now our ammani adani gujus are part
of that I don't know about that but okay
I I don't know about deep state what it
is and I don't know about the freemasons
I don't know If mani are part of that I
have no idea
really now Miss Patel says you as the
most powerful vasal on the planet a
sight to be a sight to behold yeah if it
is indeed the case
or dash says E00 EV okay once again you
asked the same question but I don't know
I don't know sorry
uh kids wipes says Empire Stri I feel
the
empires
fall by greed is the US same every
empire eventually falls whether it's
because of greed whether it's because of
complacency whether it is hubris whether
it is uh elite over protection whether
it is uh whatever usually internal
issues every empire eventually meets
that fate the US is no different
viras's Will Saudi come to rescue
Pakistan in operation too? I doubt it. I
doubt it very much. Okay. Gora TV says,
"Do you think the US is just a paper
tiger as practically they've lost every
war they've started? Even in World War
II, it was the USSR that played a major
role.
The US is great at regime change. The US
is great at bullying small nations. Um,
they won the Cold War because they
played the economic and geopolitical
game, right? Not because they defeated
the USSR militarily. World War II, it
was the USSR that actually defeated Nazi
Germany.
Um,
when was the last time the US defeated a
worthy adver adversary? They defeated
Saddam twice, but Saddam used to be
their own vasal and he was not prepared
the way Iran is.
Um,
can it's something that should be
considered seriously actually. Is the US
just a paper tiger? Well, actually, they
have the world's largest navy. No, the
Chinese is now the largest navy. The
thing that makes the US so scary is its
nuclear arsenal.
Uh the excellence of its nuclear
submarines which are everywhere.
The fact that one nuclear submarine can
launch enough missiles to destroy an
entire country,
the nuclear missiles.
um the fact that the US controls the
global economy
and has bought out a lot of people
across the world. These are the things
that makes the U that make the US an
empire. But can they fight a war against
a wellprepared adversary is a big
question today after seeing what's what
how the Americans are fairing in Iran.
It's a big big question and that really
yeah is really the US a paper tiger. I
think this war will tell us whether the
US is a paper tiger or not. Yeah, Dirhaj
Kamat says Modi in Israel said Israel is
the fatherland and India is the
motherland. I think it's pretty
disgraceful and humiliating to us like
why say that? Um
I don't know Israel is the fatherland,
India the motherland.
I am not sure if it is disgraceful or
humiliating.
Uh there are various many nations that
call their land the motherland. The
Chinese say China is the motherland.
India says motherland. Germany says
fatherland. Does Israel also say
fatherland? I'm not sure. Maybe he was
just referring to the cultural
connotations or something.
And I'm sure he was not saying that
Israel is our father. I'm sure he was
not saying that. Uh yeah. So I don't
think that was the intention. If some
people have taken it that way, maybe
maybe we should not take it that way.
Yeah. So I don't think Mr. Modi was
trying to u
to be ultra differential to Israel or to
abase India or any such thing. I don't
think so. Hanish says new files revealed
Trump said to an adult star that she
reminded him of Ivanka his daughter
after you know with her. What a
disgusting man and culture. Um
yeah I better not comment about this. I
yeah this is their culture I suppose.
Kinetic history videos says what's your
prediction on this war? Who will win?
Well, it will be good for India if
Israel if if Iran survives if India if
Iran does not get destroyed.
Will that be the eventual eventuality is
the question.
I think it is more likely than less that
Iran survives this war.
Iran will be devastated.
Iran will be devastated. It'll have
taken immense damage that will cost
hundreds of billions of dollars to
rebuild. Who will pay that? Nobody. But
I think Iran may survive. And if Iran
for Iran survival is victory, I think
Iran will win this war.
Ghoulibar says, "Check Aqua Air X and
it's interesting." What is Aqua Air on X
on X on Twitter?
What is Aqua Air? Let's see.
Let us go to X.
A Q U A
I R.
What's aqua air?
Bangaluru startup Aqua Air X unveils
India's first amphibious drone.
Outstanding. Brilliant.
Outstanding.
Raqu Air
amphibious drone capable of seamlessly
transitioning between aerial flight and
underwater operations. Well, that's
fantastic.
Cool. Love it. See, we have such
innovative people in India.
We need to promote them
and reward them. Karamjit Rahul says
Pakistan will be attacked because of US
air base. Well, in the case the US is
using Pakistani air bases for military
operations against Iran, Iran will
probably hit out at those military air
bases.
Yeah. So in case Pakistan allows the US
to use Pakistani military and air force
installations to carry out or launch
attacks on Iran, Iran will most likely
attack Pakistan and destroy or try to
destroy those those air bases or
military installations. That is very
likely very likely.
Rdra Gulba says, "What leverage does the
US have to arm twist us in supporting
them? economic leverage, all kinds of
leverage.
India wants access to the US market.
That's a huge leverage the Americans
have. Then the other leverage is
sanctions. They could impose all kinds
of sanctions on India for any pretext,
right?
Um
there must be other leverage also.
So the US has all kinds of leverage over
India. They can use Pakistan against us.
They are encircling India. There's
Pakistan, East Pakistan, West Pakistan,
Nepal
right
um
so many things
sur future of Indian IT due to these
conditions I think India's IT is going
to not do well in the future
because uh of the advent of agentic AI
systems.
Uh so India's India's IT industry is
going to be impacted by AI not by the
war conditions that we have right now.
The 2020s are turning out to be an era
of war. So that is not going to impact
Indian IT. It's the it's the rapid
advancement in AI technologies that's
going to impact it.
Uh so that's going to be bad for India.
Rubin Baskar, thank you very much sir.
Indeed.
Karthik Ayar says reports of hundreds of
Iran launchers taken out. Reports coming
from where? From the United States and
the US media and US owned social media.
Missiles will be useless. If all
launches destroyed, only drones will be
left.
See, it's possible that there is some
truth to it.
But I have seen videos where
ballistic missiles are being are being
launched by Iran without any launchers.
without launchers straight out of a hole
in the desert.
The Iranians have planned for these
things.
So yeah, I'm sure possibly hundreds of
launchers have been taken out, but the
Iranians have been planning for this.
They've built more than a 100,000
drones. You think they've not built tens
of thousands of launchers also?
But yeah,
the Americans will do their best to take
out launchers and take out all possible
infrastructure. So the longer the war
lasts, the harder it would probably be
for Iran to keep launching missiles and
drones. So eventually at some point in
time, they may reach a situation where
they can't launch missiles and drones.
Then they'll fight with by other means.
VSVS says, "Okay, this is uh annoying.
Now I don't like the term because it's a
ra racist term used against Indians. So
let's not use such a language. All
right. Thank you.
Provin Baskar says big fan. Thank you
sir. With Iran under attack and Arab
Gulf states say staying silent. Has
Islam's internal Shia Sunni fracture
becomes the west? Has it become the
West's more powerful weapon?
No. This war is not about the Shia Sunni
divide or fracture. There are plenty of
Sunni people who are coming out in
support of Iran.
Looks like this war could actually heal
the Shia Sunni schism to a certain
extent. Certain extent.
So this Shia Sunni fracture is not the
West's more powerful weapon.
That that's not the case.
See there is rivalry between the Arab
between the nations in in West Asia
mainly the Arab nations versus Israel to
some extent it is fueled by the Shia
Sunnis schism but the real reason for
this is that the West Asian Arabic
nations are American allies or vasals
and Iran is not
that's the real reason so it's not the
Shia only thing that is the cause of
this rivalry VSVS says
Amir Khan please ban
um okay Russia power says war continue
Russia gets involved India inflation
Russia will get involved if more nations
come and band up gang up with the
Americans and Israel is attacking Iran
or Russia will get involved if Iran is
doing very poorly and maybe under is
under risk of going down in certain
cases Russia will get involved otherwise
VSBs says,
"Okay." All right.
I Okay. Thank you for reporting this,
but I'm in no position to look into
who's saying what because I'm trying to
answer questions unfortunately. I will
look into these matters later on.
Yeah.
SG something. Yeah. There are so many
questions on the regular chat that I am
never able to find this individual. I'll
look into that later. Thank you.
Banikandan says Manikandan Vidand Stoic
says US reports that Russia supplied
intelligence on US radar in hard
locations which helped in precision hits
by Iran. There were reports that China
supplied arms before the start start of
operations. Is it true? Uh it is
possible. I don't know. I have not kept
track of Chinese shipments to Iran. So I
don't know what they've done. Uh but
it's possible the Chinese China may have
supplied arms to the to the Iranians
before the starts of operations. Uh
Russia most likely supplied intelligence
on US radar and third locations. Even
China must have done this and China and
Russia are both providing their uh GPS
equivalent services or better better
than GPS services to Iran. So yeah,
there is cooperation between Russia,
China and Iran
straight out of the out of the box.
Thank you very much sir or ma'am. Thank
you.
Rahul Sharma says, "Could one indirect
effect of US confrontation with with
Iran be to remind global capital that
Gulf state heaven status depends on
American guarantees?"
Well, one indirect effect of this
confrontation with Iran will be to tell
the Gulf countries that they cannot
trust American guarantees of security of
the American security umbrella. And it
will tell the entire world that the that
America's word can't be trusted.
Okay? Because America has given security
guarantees to the Gulf nations
and those guarantees have been we can
now see that the Americans can't keep
their word.
They can't.
So that's the effect it's going to have.
Goullibar says high public office like
MEA demands independence. Having close
family settled abroad can create
potential external pressure. I
completely agree with you. Yes.
straight out of the box. Thank you very
much once again, sir ma'am. Thank you.
Vsvs says, "Okay, VSVS, can you ask this
for me? So our thoughts on US office
Christian groups praying for Trump?"
Yeah, it's weird. It's weird.
I mean, the Americans are accusing the
Iranians of being fanatics, right? Isn't
this Christian fanaticism?
Yeah. in the in the white house at the
oval office in the oval office office.
Yeah, that's Christian fanatic
fanaticism. So this looks like an
American crusade, a Christian crusade
against uh an Islamic nation.
Yosti says from where do I get latest
updates on Iran Israel war? You are
sometimes late to make a video really
ready to read articles etc. Big fan for
almost 5 years. Thank you so much for
being a big fan. um latest updates I
think still the best place is Twitter or
X
okay
uh there is obviously
some suppression of news on Twitter
but still I think if you want to know
exactly what's happening right now in
real time even today the best place is
Twitter if you want to read articles and
all you can go to various uh media
outlets but those articles are written
after proper analysis and proper
drafting and all that takes hours or
maybe a day or
So an article that comes out right now,
it may be about an event that happened
maybe 5 hours ago or maybe a day ago.
But if you want real time updates, I
think X is still the place despite
the possible information sensor
censorship censorship that's happening
on X.
I would say that's the place. The
another place is Telegram. If you know
which telegram groups to follow, in that
case you get uncensored information in
almost real time from the battlefield.
But
sometimes that uncensored information
can be pretty unsettling.
So yeah,
latest updates you should one place
Twitter, another place's telegram.
Thank you. Viri WHMA says, "How much do
you rate Prime Minister Modi? Great or
average? Still a lot to do. Is it too
much to expect for him to make India
great again?
How much how do I rate Prime Minister
Modi? I think he's the best Prime
Minister we've had since 47.
I still think so. Of course, there are
frustrations
that I have that some how much more
should have been done. That frustration
will be there with everybody, right?
So I I I would say that of all the prime
ministers we've had, he he has taken
India forward the most. In 2014, India
was not where it is today. India has
gone far ahead of where it is where it
was in 2014. I agree still a lot to do.
It's probably too much to expect one man
to make India great again. It has to be
a series of leaders who all take us in
in in that direction. Then only India
can be great. One person can't make
India great. So let's not expect one
person to do everything for India.
I think there will be somebody else
after him and somebody else after that
person. It'll take two three great
leaders to do to make India great again.
H thing says many argued that India
should dump S400 and get hard and
patriot. Haha. I know who those who
those many were. I know who they were.
Yeah. Dump the S400. I know those
people. I know people who've written
articles about this. I know people who
have been arguing on on on TV and on and
on on Twitter and other places about
this. Dump the S400. Yeah. Right. Where
are they now?
Arnav Kumar J says, "What will happen to
the Chabahar port if Iran falls or or if
Iran wins? Will it trust India or a new
problem for India? Is betting on USA a
good idea?" Betting on the USA is a bad
idea. I am not anti-US.
I am just pro- India. I'm pro-
sovereignty. Betting on the US means you
agree to subordinate yourself to the US
which means you eventually at some point
in time without realizing or not become
a vasal.
That's never a good idea. So what will
happen to Chabahar port if Iran falls?
If Iran falls the US will take over
Chabahar. Simple. It's a very good port.
Very good natural harbor. So that will
happen. That's what happens if Iran
falls. The US takes over Chavahar. It
maybe sets out a military base there,
naval base. If Iran wins, what happens?
Well, if Iran wins, it it retains
Chabahar. If Iran wins, will it trust
India? Or will it be a new problem for
India? I think Iran will trust India.
Iran India may have verbally taken the
side of the Americans and Israelis or
whatever. But India hasn't done anything
that harms Iran. So, I think there may
be some bad taste left over. But overall
we have done nothing through actions
that hurts Iran. So that they will
understand.
Governor Singh says after capturing Iran
will they go will the US go for Cuba,
Greenland, Canada? What is there in the
next 10 20 years plan and how will it
impact US economy? Recession coming or
not?
What's the American plan for the next 10
20 years? And now that's a good
question. That's a good way of zooming
out of where we are right now and
looking at the big picture. The next say
the immediate objective of the US is to
take control of all the major oil
producing regions in the world.
By doing that you make China completely
dependent on Russia and then maybe you
can do something about Russia which
isolates China completely. So in the
next 10 20 years the the Americans want
to end all potential threats to the US.
What are the potential threats? China,
Russia,
Iran,
India.
Now, India may not want to threaten the
US ever, but the US still considers
India to be a future potential threat.
So, next 10, 20 years, the US wants to
end all those threats, neutralize all
those threats once and for all. That is
their plan. That's their goal. That's
their objective.
After capturing Iran, will the US go for
Cuba, Green and China? I think the US
can go for Cuba even now. What can Cuba
do about it? Right now, I mean, a couple
of days ago, the Americans were
bombarding Ecuador.
Ecuador is the is a small country in the
north northwest of South America.
The Americans were bombarding Ecuador a
couple of days ago. So, the Americans
have the ability to to take Cuba right
now if they want. I think Cuba could be
one of the next targets of the US. Well,
it it makes sense as as part of their
Monro Doctrine uh the renewed Monro
doctrine to take Cuba.
Uh Greenland Canada
uh the US will take Greenland.
Maybe not dur possession of Greenland
but definitely de facto possession of
Greenland. The Americans already have de
facto possession of Greenland.
at least to some extent. Maybe they will
extend the extent to which they have de
facto possession of Greenland. Canada,
well,
I don't know about Canada. Greenland
definitely they will expand and
consolidate their their possession of of
that territory. Cuba, it's possible
even likely perhaps that they will go
after Cuba.
Canada, I'm not so sure.
So yeah uh so that seems to be the the
thing. Yeah. Recession coming possibly
recession coming especially if the
straight of hormones remains closed for
a while. Recession could come all over
the world
hopefully not India.
Empty box says trad in study tradin
study start with im cosmic id. So why
not? I have no idea what you're saying
sir. I have no idea whatsoever. Sorry.
Very sorry.
Scooby says, "What do you think about
UAE's status as a safe haven?" Now, will
expat hubs like Dubai be impacted given
how many move there for a better quality
of life? Look, if this war goes on for
months, the UA status as a safe haven
will be very badly impacted.
If the war ends ends
and Iran is defeated, then slowly people
may limp back come back to Dubai and so
on. If the war ends without an Iranian
defeat, nobody will come back to Dubai.
Yeah. Uh lots of people have fled Dubai,
I've heard. But I I I know personally I
know that there are many people who are
still stuck there.
But once the airport opens and you're
able to move out, most of them will move
out at least for the time being as long
as the war is going on. We don't want to
be in Dubai when the war is next door.
Obviously, when missiles could come in,
drones may come in. So once the war
ends, it will depend on how it ends. If
it ends with an American victory, I
think people will go back to Dubai. If
it ends without
an Iranian defeat, people will stay
away. Yeah. which is a it's a shame
right Dubai was providing this this
great safe haven for people from across
the world this oasis of excellence
for Indians for people from other
countries terrible
uh Tommy Versati says why didn't India
condemn the torpedo attack because it
was done by the Americans India doesn't
verbally condemn anything America does
okay India is trying to not antagonize
the United States That's what India is
trying its best to do. That's why India
did not condemn the assassination of Mr.
Kame and that's why India did not
condemn the torpedo attack that killed
more than 100 Iranian soldiers sailors
because India does not want to
antagonize the Americans. That's why
Orodash says by 2032 if we shift to EV
E00 hydrogen fuel for vehicles will it
decrease pressure on the government?
What will the US do then? As India will
be energy sovereign.
If India becomes energy sovereign or
close to energy sovereign, it will
significantly reduce the pressure on the
government of India. But you see
when it comes to
fourwheelers, two wheelers etc. When it
comes to trains, you can have
electrification,
you can use hydrogen fuel, you can use
lithium ion batteries and so on and so
forth. But when it comes to aircraft and
ships, you can't
use electricity.
You can't use batteries, lithiumion
batteries, you can't use hydrogen fuel,
right?
uh
so the right way to become energy
sovereign is to discover
India's own oil reserves
but of course by moving to electric more
and more especially for four-wheers two
wheelers etc it can significantly
decrease the pressure until we find our
own oil reserves so yes it'll be great
for India if we if we do this and that's
why India is trying its best to become u
to to transition to electric electric as
soon as possible
Right. Uh what will the US do if India
becomes energy sovereign? Well, the US
what can the US do in that case? Not
much.
At least in that department, the US
can't do much. Unless India discovers
oil fields offshore, then the Americans
may make life difficult for India in
some way offshore.
Shubamat music. Thank you very much.
Shubamat music. Music music. Nice. Thank
you. Welcome to the membership of the
channel. Priyan Shukumar says, "How long
will the Middle East be involved in
this?
As long as the war lasts, you mean in
the war? How long will the war last?"
Depends on whether the Americans have
the appetite for a really long drawout
war
or whether it'll become economically
unviable for them. in which case they
will go go to plan B which is funding
terrorists and militias like like ISIS
and the Kurds but even that may not
really work out well. So this most
likely is going to be a monthsl long if
not yearslong mess that the Americans
have got and the Israelis have got the
Middle East involved in most likely it's
going to be long drawn out of air.
UPSC motivation says recently visited
China safe to say they've built their
infra ready for the future where is
India crippling infra do you think south
way more developed
um so so China has
China knows what he's trying to do
and China gets things done
so China has China's aspiration
is to replace and displace the US is the
world's sole superpower by about 2050.
When you have that sort of a huge
massive goal, you're going to have
worked very hard towards that, right?
Especially when you are a professional
government and so on as opposed to
professional politicians. So the Chinese
have done a great job of building the
infrastructure. They also are still
working on it. They also have gaps but
they are doing a great job. In India, we
have this culture of rent seeking,
right? So, we have disparities in
various parts of the nation. East versus
west, north versus south and so on. And
these are problems India needs to fix.
Anand says, "Going to South Korea, you
say hard being moved. Should I worry?"
No, you you don't need to worry. No, you
don't need to worry. It's okay. It'll be
fine.
Rahul says, "Rels have invested into
India nse. I've heard about the national
sock stock exchange the roshells. What
is that thing? Let me find out.
Okay, let's see.
India national stock exchange
Rothschilds.
What is this news? Rosschill and company
have a presence in India had has a
presence in India with the Mumbai based
team focusing on advisory services.
However, the National Stock Exchange of
India is owned by various domestic and
global institutions and individuals with
no direct ownership or controlled by the
Roship family or the firm.
Um,
Bombay Stock Exchange a separate entity.
Is it the Bombay?
Is it the Bombay Stock Exchange?
Every time it gives you a different
answer. This is the problem with AI,
right? So Roshillian company has been
appointed by the National Stock Exchange
of India as an independent adviser to
oversee its low long awaited IPO.
Okay. So Roshillian company is managing
the IPO process including advisor
selection.
Okay.
All right. So that's the deal.
Rahul says what's the Rochil family and
13 families theory? I don't know. I
haven't studied that so I don't know.
Vidhi Parik says NSC to engage Roshchill
as adviser to for its IPO. Your
thoughts?
Well, I see I've heard of various rumors
and and theories about the Roshian
family that they control the world and
so on, but I haven't studied that so I
don't know about them.
Maybe it's high time I update my
knowledge.
So my for the So they are engaged for
the IPO for the NS inc. What are my
thoughts right now? I don't have any
thoughts about this because I don't know
about the ros shields.
If what if the if the stories about them
are true then it's kind of concerning
but I don't know right now
Spider-Man says Indian education system
is garbage as well as news channels
right yes yes yes
nikud Sharma says is nuclear threat
imminent in our lifetime I hope not
right now it's not imminent but if the
Iran war doesn't go the way the
Americans in Israel is like there could
be something
of
there could be is the possibility of
nuclear weapons being used. I hope it's
it doesn't ever happen in our lifetime
or in anybody's lifetime but who knows a
house says Rosschild Rockefeller Aster
Bundy Collins Dupont Freeman Kennedy Lee
Onasis Reynolds Russell and Vani own the
US Federal Reserve deep state question
mark I don't know I don't know it's
possible but I don't know I don't have
the facts
says who are Frankists and what is
Frankism I am not
sure about that. Let's find out
together, shall we?
Who are Frankists and what is Frankism?
Frankists were followers of 18th century
Polish Jewish pseudo messiah Jacob Frank
who led a radical anti- antinomeian and
messianic movement called Frankism.
emerging from sab sabatianism in podia.
Frankism rejected traditional Talmudic
law engaging in controversial rituals
and ultimately promoting promoting mass
conversion to Catholicism. The movement
which claimed thousands of followers
combined Jewish, Christian and Islamic
elements and so on. Okay. So I I was not
aware of this. All right.
Vishwish Vish Wish Nyak says namaskar
Rijit. Namaskar. My suggestion for
electronics in India is having some good
amount of people in embedded systems and
doing high volume low-end manufacturing.
High volume, low Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. I agree with you. Yes.
That's how you start off. You start off
with high volume and low-end stuff. Why
not? India needs to become a
manufacturing nation, major
manufacturing nation. Start with
anything. Start with nuts, bolts,
needles, screwdrivers, whatever. When it
comes to electronics, yes. high high
volume low-end manufacturing. I
absolutely agree with you. I'm not sure
what embedded systems are. Let's find
out what embedded systems are.
What are embedded systems?
Okay. Embedded system is a specialized
computing device designed to perform
specific tasks combining both hardware
and software. Yeah. Okay. Often within a
larger mechanical or electrical system.
Unlike general purpose computers, they
are optimized for reliability, power
efficiency, and so on. Okay. It's a
fusion or synthesis of hardware and
software systems. Yeah,
I agree with you. I think it's a great
suggestion. Great suggestion.
David Joti Saha says why China is
attacking Taiwan in the situation. What?
Really?
When did that happen?
When did China attack Taiwan?
Really?
Let me see.
I
Dubai Marina is trending. Islamabad is
tending trending.
Conor McGregor is trending. Look, if
China has invaded Taiwan, I would know
about it. I don't think China has thus
far
attack Taiwan.
Karthik says, "You are absolutely
correct. US officials openly saying that
they want to steal Iran in oil. Yes.
Yes. Yes. Yes. They're blatantly openly
saying they want to
they don't use the word steal. They say
they want to
take over Iranian oil from what? From
terrorists or whatever. So they
essentially that's what they're saying.
They want to steal the oil openly.
They're saying it blatantly.
Rahul Patel. Thank you very much. Rahul
Patel G.
Putin says is it time for Chava
doctrine? they mandro doctrine
I I would not have any objections to
that but first to enforce that you need
the capabilities that's why India needs
to militarize
to enforce an Indian mandro doctrine or
the cha doctrine you would need to have
sufficient naval assets to control a
large portion of the ocean that's
relevant to our interests
which means you would need
hundreds of more warships than India has
and definitely at least 50 submarines. I
would say close to 90 or 100 submarines.
That's what India needs. Only then can
you actually implement or enforce such a
doctrine. Otherwise, it's just words.
So I I think it's time I think it should
be done.
Gajjapati Deva says views on the Odisha
famine of 1866 by the British. They
still hero worship British guy Raven
Shaw Sahib. In fact, a big college is
named after him there. So they the
people wor her hero worship people
because of what they are taught in the
education system. Maybe in the textbooks
they are being taught that the Raven
show guy was the guy who tried to
prevent the famine instead of causing
it. Right? And when your teachers say
speak highly about somebody, you're
going to automatically feel that this is
the right thing to do. Especially when
the your college is named after this
guy. It's it's this is the problem in
India. India is still deeply deeply
mentally coronized and nothing has been
done to change these things.
Amrit K says what will be the impact now
that India has allowed Roshchel and
company who were funding wars before to
enter the Indian financial market
through NC IPO.
So like I said, I am not really familiar
with the history of the Russian family,
but in case all the stories about them
are true and that they they really are
part of the deep state or whatever and
were funding wars and and and
have nefarious designs, let's say
possibly against India,
then it is a very very concerning
development.
What could be the impact? I'm not sure.
But if this is the case, then it's
concerning. Why can't why don't you hire
an Indian Indian company to do this? Why
do you need to hire a foreign company
and that to
rot shield possibly? I mean if if the
stories about them are true.
So I think it's it's concerning. I'm not
sure what the impact could be but it's
definitely concerning him. Why why hire
them? Why not hire an Indian company?
Don't we have experts in India?
Kit Krit Gupta says
former foes Iran Iraq now friends
question mark thank you for recording
these live streams you're very welcome
sir you make my daily miserable drive
commits to Gurawa
internationalformational
I'm so I'm I'm so glad I'm glad thank
you so much thank you former foes Iran
and Iraq now friends well they're no
longer foes at least I can tell you that
because Iran is Iraq is no longer a
sovereign nation
Iraq is is an entity that's controlled
controlled by the US. It's owned by the
US. Not djour but de facto.
Um
but but Iraq as we know has a large Shia
population. 40 to 50% of them are Shia.
And that obviously makes them friends of
Iran.
And during Saddam Hussein's time when
Iran and Iraq went to war, that war was
injured by the US because Saddam was a
US ally, a US puppet, US wasal. and the
Americans wanted to use Iran Iraq to to
bleed Iran. So that's why there was a
war between the two nations which ended
in a stalemate.
So they're not exactly friends. They're
not enemies either anymore.
But I'll tell you what, the Americans
will use Iraqi territory
to push
insurgents and terrorists into Iran
if they go ahead with the plan of regime
change. So yeah, there is that that for
sure.
Prattana says seems Obama has leverage
over Israel. I am not aware of that at
all. Does he I'm not sure in what way.
Obama I mean if there's a deep state
Obama will definitely be part of it. You
know does he have leverage over Israel?
Obama did not have a great relationship
with Israel. He had a very fractious and
hostile relationship with Netanyahu and
overall was pretty negative towards
Israel. So that's what I know. I'm not
sure about what leverage he may have.
Gigad says biggest racist group towards
Indians on X are MAGA supporters. You
may be right about that. Yeah. Yeah.
That's also the Chinese, the Pakistanis
and so many more. But yeah, MAGA. Yeah.
Um Copesh Desai. Thank you very much.
Cop Desai G. Thank you sir. I think it's
a mailed name. Thank you. Thank you.
Spade says, "Sir, make me the mod. I'll
deal with these racists. Uh, next time
I'll look into that. Right now, I can't
in real time make you the moderator, but
thank you for the offer."
Vari Valiki says, "What percentage of
our GDP should ideally be allocated to
defense current considering we currently
spend about 2%." I would say for the
next 10 years, it should be 5%.
If we do that, it's going to have
obviously we'll have to find that money
from someone else. uh reallocated from
somewhere else into defense which means
we may have to stop the largely be bhana
yojana and some other yojas and some
freebie yojas and all that but that's I
think it's fine
so I think considering the fact that the
2020s are increasingly an era of war and
we have a major war in our own backyard
I think and and considering the kind of
enemies we have Pakistan which is the US
puppet ally Basal in China who obviously
we know their history with India. They
have been extremely unfriendly towards
India. Considering the situation, India
should I would say allocate 5% of its
GDP towards defense because this 2% of
of GDP towards defense which goes into
defense. A lot of it goes into salaries
and pensions.
A lot of it goes there. So I think it
should be 5%.
Iran war is going to embolden some
countries for sure.
It's going to embolden some countries
especially if uh Iran resists and
survives. Yeah. Empty boxes. Old Indian
study started with Aam Brahmasi. So now
so why nashioid
old India study started with Aam
Brahmasma? So why
natioid?
I don't know what natioid means. So I
not able to understand the question. I
suppose there must be restrictions on
the amount of characters you can type or
something. But I'm sorry I'm not able to
understand the question. Natioid
Anil says is the world now not realizing
the US double standards.
I look most of the world simply
believes what the media tells them and
the media most of it is controlled by
the US.
So the media will justify everything.
The media will try to explain everything
you know that makes all American actions
sound very rational. So the Americans
are saying we our objective is to take
over Iranian oil from the terrorists.
Which terrorists? the Iran Iranian
government but if you believe what
believe this narrative then you won't
see double standards so yeah
Shubam go says the Americans have openly
said they don't want India to be another
another China why what why do you think
they're so open about it because they
are so open about it
because they believe that they have
India in their grasp and there's nothing
India can do about it so they can be
arrogant and condescending and p and rub
your nose into it. That's what they
think. They are openly saying this
because they are certain that they have
India in their grasp. I wonder what
makes them so certain about it. But
otherwise, they would not say it. Okay.
Messile says, "Imagine a reality where
where there are no Abrahamic religions
and countries are following their
indigenous durms like Europe, Greek and
Roman gods.
Persians, Zoroastranism, Egypt, their
thing, their their own religion. Well,
it would be a very different world.
Yeah. Would be a very different world.
It would be like the way the world was
2,000 years ago.
Priyanki Chakraati says, "Has Iran come
conclusions with Arab countries? Is that
true? If yes, has the US officially lost
the war?" Uh the last I saw the
government of Iran said that we are no
longer going to be launching attacks on
the Arab nations. The attacks we have
launched were not on the nations but on
the US military bases from which uh
attacks were being carried out on Iran
and now we will not be doing that. So it
means that Iran
has most likely destroyed or
incapacitated
the American military bases on these
nations territories whether it is UAE,
whether it is Saudi Arabia, whether it
is Kuwait, whether it is Bahrain, Oman,
whoever.
So that's why they have said that they
will not attack anymore because they
must have neutralized this these bases.
Does it mean the US has officially lost
the war? No, the US can still fight and
it's still fighting. They're still
pounding the Han and other cities and
causing god knows how much destruction.
Uh the Americans can use Iraq and Syria
as launching pads for attacks on Iran.
They can also use Israeli territory for
attacks on Iran.
So the Americans have not lost the war
yet. I think Iran is still on the back
foot. Okay. The Americans are still the
stronger party.
But looks like the balance of balance of
power or matters in the war is shifting
slowly. So it's not that the US has
officially lost the war at this point in
time. That's not the case.
Bulra Singh, thank you very much. Bulra
Bulra Singh Gary Arian says, "Is
Chanakini still applicable in today's
world?" It is 100% absolutely applicable
in today's world. The Americans are the
biggest exponents of Chanakini.
Chatanya Modak says India plays its card
pretty well given shelter to one of the
Iranian ships citing technical slag
snag. Now Iran possibly can't launch
attack missiles at us even if American
ships use our ports or for temporary
maintenance or or refueling.
um we did the right thing by giving
shelter to an Iranian ship and that by
doing that by taking that action we have
sent a message to the Americans that we
will we will do what what we think is
right we don't need your guidance
and and your approval
um but does it mean Iran can't launch
attacks at us even if American ships use
our ports for temporary maintenance of
refuel? I think it makes it less likely
for Iran to do that. because we have a
bunch of their sailors in our custody or
under our protection.
But it doesn't mean that India should
now allow the Americans to use our port
for attacks on Iran or or as part of
what they're doing in this war.
So India's play a good India has done
the right thing I would say. But if
India then decides to give American
warships access to our ports, I don't
think that's the right move.
adustad
vin
says would the global Islamists get
emboldened if at the end of the day US
and Israel don't succeed in removing the
current Iranian regime
I think the globe the people who are
regarded as global Islamists are not
Shia they are Sunnis
and I I'm sure they'll be pleased that
an Islamic nation has been able to
withstand the assault from the US and
Iran
will it embolden the global Islamists
I'm not sure what Islamism is and
Islamists are and all but overall it
will make the Islamic world
um happy
Vijay Patel says when do we will
graduate from third power third world to
great power it will take a lot of hard
work for us to do that. Okay, right now
we are a third world nation.
For us to become a middle power or a
middle income nation,
it will take us 20 years.
20 years
if we if we play our cards right, this
is a long process. It's a slow process.
I would love it if it happens next
weekend, but I would love it. But it's
not that easy.
It's going to be a long time long long
long process and it'll be very difficult
and there's no guarantee we will
actually achieve this. It will depend on
our leadership and how resilient they
are.
Nares, thank you very much. Narish Gutin
says US China nikat nikat na ab
kajab namave
very funny. Thank you.
Mish says, "Do you believe assassination
attempt on Modi?" I have no idea. I have
no information about this. There are all
kinds of rumors on social media. I don't
know what to make of it. I I don't pay
attention to rumors that don't have any
factual basis to back them up.
Uh Anil says, "The end of US dominance
has started. Your view? It's possible. I
will still not make a judgment. I'll
wait for this war to take its course and
then we will see very clearly. But
already
already the war has gone very badly for
the US. They're having to hide what's
happening.
Yeah.
So clearly
they are not as dominant as what the
world imagined them to be.
Gojo says minor disagreement with your
thesis of US treating Russia, China,
Iran and maybe India's threats because
these are non-As that metric India the
US would want to neutralize Israel too.
No, the US
has a special relationship with Isra
with Israel.
The US does not treat each nation the
same way.
The US gives unconditional support to
Israel even when it harms US interests.
Case in point, the Americans allowed
Israel to drag them into this war
prematurely.
Right?
So the US doesn't treat India the way it
treats Israel. The US doesn't treat
Israel the way it treats Russia. Every
nation is different.
And the US does treat Russia, China,
Iran, and India as threats.
Not Israel. It does not treat Israel as
a threat.
Ustad says, "Don't you think that global
Islamic terrorism can't be disar? I
don't discuss this matter. I stay out of
this matter." Yeah. Sorry. Sorry about
that. I never discuss this.
Empty boxes previous aam brahasmi
question. So why national identity?
Uh
now I'll have to go and dig out your
previous question because I don't
remember what it was. When I take 80 90
questions in a day after 5 minutes I
forget what the previous question was
and especially when the question came
like 78
before okay I'm not able to find it.
Sorry sir.
Why national identity?
still don't know the question. Sorry. If
you can put the entire question in one
one super chat then I'll be able to
understand. I'm sorry I don't remember
what the previous fragment of the
question was and I'm not able to find it
because there are hundreds of questions
out there. Sorry sir. Sorry so much.
Genuinely sorry.
Narish says, "If you don't believe the
assassination attempt, why did Putin
pick up pick Mr. Modi up and sat in the
car for an hour and went outside inside
together in China's visit?" Because
maybe there was electronic snooping
happening and maybe Mr. Putin and Mr.
Modi wanted to discuss something inside
the car in a way that the Chinese can't
snoo on them through electronic means.
And maybe they wanted to discuss some
things they can't discuss on the phone.
There are multiple explanations beside
that assassination attempt explanation.
Let your imagination run a little right.
Okay. So there are other explanations
too apart from the assassination attempt
uh theory.
Deepak says you mentioned earlier how
strong US is may but we see its weapon
system failing militarily. Operation
Zindur Iran. Do we still need to fear
in taking decisions fearing US military
capabilities and economically we are
opening to new markets? I think we
should still fear them. Let's not say
that oh yes yes yes has lost this war
and US is weapons are weak.
No
India has to take the US very seriously.
Let's not start celebrating that
everything is failing. It's the American
military doctrine that is deficient and
obsolete and outdated. Their weapons are
outstanding. Okay.
User says how to become dictator and
change India for the good. I don't know.
I wish I knew.
Study the great dictators and how they
came to power and then be a good
dictator.
Okay, it's that's it. That's the end of
today's live stream. I suppose there's
no more live uh super chats. Thank you
so much everybody. It's been more than 4
hours. More than 4 hours.
Uh thank you so much for your questions
and I'm going to end this live stream
right now. I'll do the next one pretty
soon because there's so much happening
in the war. Give me a couple of days.
We'll have another live stream. Until
then, take care. Keep asking questions.
Keep raising your standards. Keep
learning. Thank you. I'll see you very
soon. Bye-bye. Good night. Good day for